<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-15865</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGGDZADCFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940707
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  07 JUL 94 / People: Owners Abroad
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Peter Phillipson, marketing director (international region) for United
Distillers, has been appointed commercial director of OWNERS ABROAD; Tony
Coleman joins as group human resources director from Grand Met.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Owners Abroad Group.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P4725 Tour Operators.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 17
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-15885</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGGDZACSFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940707
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  07 JUL 94 / Bus advert ban
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Cumbria Motor Services, which operates the majority of bus services in the
county, has banned cigarette and alcohol advertising from its buses.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Cumbria Motor Services.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P4111 Local and Suburban Transit.
    P73   Business Services.
    P12   Coal Mining.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>MGMT  Management &amp; Marketing.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 11
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-15933</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGGDZABGFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940707
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  07 JUL 94 / Rights workers in peril, says Amnesty
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By REUTER
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   LONDON
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Human rights workers around the world are falling victim to the kind of
torture, ill-treatment and other violations they are trying to prevent, the
human rights group Amnesty International says today, in its annual report
for 1993, Reuter reports from London.
Police beatings, arrests and executions without trial and mass killings have
been reported, despite a climate that increasingly highlights the importance
of human rights, the report says.
'Human rights defenders often became the first victims of governments trying
to build a good human rights image abroad and fearful of the damage human
rights activists can do to that image.'
The report, covering 151 countries, found that prisoners of conscience were
held in 63 countries, more than 100,000 political prisoners were held
without charge or trial in 53, more than 112 governments tortured or
ill-treated prisoners, and political killings by the state took place in 61
nations. Some 2,000 people were executed in 32 countries last year.
'We are also trying to draw attention to the fact that these things are not
inevitable. . . they are not flukes,' Mr Derek Evans, head of Amnesty's Asia
and Pacific research division, said. 'They are implemented as policy by
governments.'
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9721 International Affairs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 6
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-15981</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGGDZAHOFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940706
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 JUL 94 / World News in Brief: Blaze shuts Gotthard link
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
The 17km Gotthard road tunnel, Europe's longest and an important link for
Italy with the rest of Europe, is expected to stay closed until Saturday
after a truck blaze inside the tunnel.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>CHZ  Switzerland, West Europe.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P4785 Inspection and Fixed Facilities.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
International Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16103</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGFD2ADUFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940706
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 JUL 94 / People: Non-executive directors
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
David Barnes is retiring from THORN EMI.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Thorn EMI.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3561 Pumps and Pumping Equipment.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  People.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 20
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16115</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGFD2ADIFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940706
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 JUL 94 / People: Non-executive directors
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Andrew West, joint md of corporate finance at GUINESS MAHON, at CROSSROADS
OIL GROUP; Stanford Bardsley and M Soenderup have resigned.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Crossroads Oil Group.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P1311 Crude Petroleum and Natural Gas.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  People.
    PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 20
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16120</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGFD2ADDFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940706
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 JUL 94 / People: Non-executive directors
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Mike Allardice at GOVETT AMERICAN ENDEAVOUR FUND.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Govett American Endeavor Fund.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6726 Investment Offices, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 20
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16128</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGFD2AC5FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940706
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 JUL 94 / People: Whatman
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
David Smith, former head of group research and engineering at BP and a
member of the Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council, has been
appointed director of research and development at WHATMAN.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Whatman.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3569 General Industrial Machinery, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 20
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16220</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGFD2AAIFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940706
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 JUL 94 / World News in Brief: Dahmer attacked in jail
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
US serial killer Jeffrey Dahmer was slightly wounded when another inmate
tried to cut his throat using a homemade razor weapon at the Columbia
Correctional Institute at Portage, Wisconsin. Dahmer is serving 15 life
terms for 17 murders.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>COZ  Colombia, South America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9223 Correctional Institutions.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16263</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGEERAFZFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940705
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  05 JUL 94 / Commodities and Agriculture: Free access to plant genetic
resources assured - Geoff Tansey reports on an agreement to put gene
collections under intergovernmental control
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By GEOFF TANSEY
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
A new international agreement, guaranteeing equitable access to plant
genetic resources should be signed within a few months.
This follows the conclusion last Friday of the second session of the
Intergovernmental Committee of the Convention on Biological Diversity in
Nairobi, Kenya, where delegates agreed that there should be no intellectual
property rights governing the use of the 500,000 crop samples held in the
gene banks of 11 international agricultural research centres.
The committee gave 'strong support for finalising the agreement between the
United Nations Food and Agriculture Organisation and the international
research centres as soon as possible'.
It will put the various collections under centralised intergovernmental
control under the management of the FAO's Commission on Plant Genetic
Resources.
The agreement means that the collections will not be the centres' assets but
will be globally-owned resources and the centres will manage them as
trustees not owners, according to Dr Geoff Hawtin, director of the
International Plant Genetic Resources Institute.
The centres will be charged with the responsibility of ensuring continued
availability of materials under free access.
There will also be no intellectual property rights (patents or plant
breeder's rights) on those materials in the collections, which mainly come
from developing countries, and this condition will be passed on to
recipients of the samples.
The institute has the lead role in dealing with plant genetic resources
among the 17 centres funded by the Consultative Group on International
Agricultural Research, an informal group of donors. Each centre, however, is
an independent legal entity governed by a board of trustees. Every year,
more than 120,000 germplasm accessions from the collections and 500,000
samples of improved materials are distributed by the centres, mainly to
developing countries.
The agreement has already been accepted by the FAO's governing council, the
commission and the individual centres.
The opening of the Nairobi meeting was overshadowed by accusations by some
non-governmental organisations that the World Bank was attempting to seize
control of the consultative group's activities regarding plant genetic
resources and to delay signing of any agreements until 1996.
These fears were rejected by Mr Ismail Serageldin, chairman of the
consultative group and a vice president of the World Bank, as based on
'fanciful guesswork not backed up by facts'.
However, Mr Henk Hobbelink, director of Genetic Resources Action
International (Grain) says that in a letter sent before the meeting he told
one of the non-governmental organisations that it would be 'foolhardy to
lock into agreements' before then.
In a statement issued to the meeting, Dr Serageldin said: 'The CGIAR is
committed to carrying out the responsibilities of trusteeship (over the
genetic resources in its gene banks) in concert with FAO and its Commission
on Plant Genetic Resources, and with the contracting parties to the
Convention on Biological Diversity'.
Mr Hawtin welcomes the 'clear message from Nairobi that says sign'. The
consultative group would like to sign the agreement but since it is not a
legal body it can only do so if each centre delegates its signature to the
group chairman. This is what is likely to happen, believes Mr Hawtin; but he
sees possible delays if some centre boards still have to meet to give
approval.
'I'd rather see a quick signature than delays,' he says, as would the
non-governmental organisations, which welcome the Nairobi meeting's call for
an agreement as soon as possible. They see it as an important step in
ensuring equitable access to the world's genetic resources.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>KEZ  Kenya, Africa.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P873  Research and Testing Services.
    P01   Agricultural Production-Crops.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>RES  R&amp;D spending.
    TECH  Patents &amp; Licences.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 34
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16280</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGEERAFIFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940705
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  05 JUL 94 / International Company News: State-owned Korean groups most
profitable
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By JOHN BURTON
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   SEOUL
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Four state-controlled companies reported the biggest net profits in South
Korea last year, while three trading companies had the largest turnover,
according to an analysis by the Korea Management Association.
Korea Telecom, which is gradually being privatised, had the highest profits
at Won470bn (Dollars 583.8m). Korea Electric Power and Pohang Iron &amp; Steel,
both stock exchange listed, had net profits of Won419bn and Won295bn
respectively. Korea Heavy Industries &amp; Construction followed with Won247bn.
Hyundai Heavy Industries, the country's leading shipbuilder, had the biggest
net profits in the private industrial sector at Won221bn. Samsung
Corporation, trading arm of the Samsung group, had the largest sales at
Won13,321bn.
The trading subsidiaries of Hyundai and Daewoo followed at Won11,046bn and
Won9,534bn respectively, while Samsung Life Insurance ranked fourth at
Won8,863bn.
Samsung Electronics had the largest sales among manufacturers, with
Won8,155bn.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Korea Telecommunications.
    Korea Electric Power Corp.
    Pohang Iron and Steel.
    Korea Heavy Industries and Construction.
    Hyundai Heavy Industries.
    Samsung.
    Samsung Life Insurance.
    Samsung Electronics.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>KRZ  South Korea, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P4813 Telephone Communications, Ex Radio.
    P4911 Electric Services.
    P3312 Blast Furnaces and Steel Mills.
    P3731 Ship Building and Repairing.
    P6719 Holding Companies, NEC.
    P6311 Life Insurance.
    P3679 Electronic Components, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Company News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 31
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16300</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGEERAEYFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940705
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  05 JUL 94 / UK Company News: Seton makes Pounds 3.5m purchase
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Seton Healthcare Group has acquired the Medised brand from Macarthy
Laboratories for Pounds 3.5m cash.
Medised is a leading over-the-counter product for colds and flu in children.
The acquisition represents another step in Seton's strategy of building a
portfolio of established healthcare brands, which the group can promote
through its sales network to pharmacists and consumers.
In the 12 months to June 30, unaudited sales attributable to the Medised
brand were about Pounds 725,000.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Seton Healthcare Group.
    Macarthy Laboratories.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P2834 Pharmaceutical Preparations.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Mergers &amp; acquisitions.
    TECH  Products &amp; Product use.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 28
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16397</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGEERAB7FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940705
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  05 JUL 94 / Litigants listed
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Forty people have been blacklisted by the courts as vexatious litigants
since 1983, Lord Chancellor Lord Mackay of Clashfern said in a Lords written
reply last night.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9211 Courts.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 11
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16408</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGEERABWFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940705
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  05 JUL 94 / Warning over Forth crossing
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Traffic across the Firth of Forth is likely to grow by 50 per cent between
1990 and 2010, says an independent study into plans for a privately financed
second Forth road bridge.
The report for the Scottish Office said that neither a new bridge nor public
transport improvements in isolation would resolve the problems of increased
traffic which could lead to regular 10-mile tailbacks.
The study was carried out by MVA Consultancy, Oscar Faber TPA and
Environmental Resource Management.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9621 Regulation, Administration of Transportation.
    P1622 Bridge, Tunnel and Elevated Highway.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 10
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16421</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGEERABJFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940705
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  05 JUL 94 / Taiwan tries to buy time for its push to rejoin UN: Taipei
is expected to advocate a slow development of its cross-strait ties with
Beijing
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By LAURA TYSON
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Fearful of becoming irretrievably ensnared in China's web, Taiwan is
attempting to slow development of cross-strait ties to win time to build
support for its attempts to rejoin the international community.
In its first white paper on China policy, to be released today, the
government is expected to advocate a go-slow approach to the rapprochement
launched with historic talks between the two sides in Singapore in April
1993. After seven years' detente, the paper comes amid a sharp escalation in
cross-strait tensions since the March 31 deaths of 24 Taiwanese tourists in
China's Zhejiang Province.
While Taiwan business backs closer ties with China, most Taiwanese remain
profoundly distrustful of Beijing's leaders. The tourist killings played
into the hands of President Lee Teng-hui, who is using the incident to
further his agenda of getting the world to recognise Taiwan as an
independent sovereign state, observers say.
It is rumoured among Taipei politicians that shortly after Mr Lee became
president following the death of Mr Chiang Ching-kuo in 1988, opposition
leaders asked him to seek formal Taiwanese independence from China. Mr Lee
is said to have replied: 'Just give me time'. The story may be apocryphal,
but Mr Lee's record speaks for itself.
The Taiwan-born agricultural economist built up a power base from virtually
nil, presided over a transition to democracy and in early 1993 shoved off
the political stage the military-backed mainlanders who ran the country for
over 40 years.
Weeks later, he launched a campaign to rejoin the UN, which Taiwan left in
1972, after that body switched recognition to Beijing.
In the past year, he and his ministers have globe-trotted constantly, trying
to drum up international support for entry into the UN and other
multilateral bodies from which Taiwan has long been excluded because of
China's objections.
Taipei maintains full diplomatic relations with 29 countries. Beijing
threatens to break off ties with any country which formally recognises
Taipei. As a permanent member of the UN security council, it can veto
Taiwan's entry. But Mr Lee's tactics are causing consternation, not only in
Beijing, which views the island as a renegade province, but also in
Washington, Taiwan's closest ally and benefactor.
'Taiwan has turned into a kind of Frankenstein's monster,' observes Mr
Parris Chang, a lawmaker from the pro-independence opposition Democratic
Progressive party (DPP). 'The US fostered Taiwan's democratic development
and some might say the policy worked too well. Now the US has to live with
the consequences.'
The US strategy seems to be simply to wait. The Clinton administration
recently completed a comprehensive review of US policy toward Taiwan, the
first in 15 years. Minor though symbolically important changes in the US
stance are expected to be announced shortly. But there will be no change in
the US's 'one-China' policy dating from the late 1970s acknowledging
Beijing's claim over Taiwan.
Taiwan now experiences a cacophony of views on the island's identity and
future. The debate is further shrouded by a haze of rhetoric emanating from
the government. Because China threatens to use force should Taiwan declare
independence, the ruling Nationalist party, or Kuomintang, persists in
larding its assertions that 'the Republic of China on Taiwan is a sovereign
state' with dubious claims that its 'transitional two-China policy' is a
interim measure whose ultimate goal is reunification.
'The Republic of China on Taiwan is already an independent nation by
whatever definition,' says Mr Hanson Chien, the KMT spokesman. 'There's no
need to antagonise the PRC and invite a war.'
Public opinion is divided. A government-commissioned survey in late June
found 12 per cent of Taiwanese support independence, 21 per cent support
reunification, and 56 per cent prefer to maintain the status quo. A Gallup
poll conducted shortly after the tourist killings showed support for
independence at an all-time high of 27 per cent.
'China should realise the only reason more people don't openly support
Taiwan's independence is because they are afraid China will attack, not
because they want reunification,' says Ms Maysing Yang, head of the DPP's
foreign affairs department.
About the only matter on which there is a national consensus is that Taiwan
should rejoin the UN, and is it on this aim that President Lee appears to
have staked his hopes.
Ultimately the US will play a decisive role in Taiwan's future, says Mr Wang
Chien-shien of the KMT-breakaway Chinese New party. 'It is in the US's
long-term interest to have an independent Taiwan. Some day, when it suits
their purposes, the US will play the Taiwan card against China. Now the time
is not mature.'
By March 1996 at the latest, Taiwan will hold direct presidential elections
for the first time. Mr Lee's popularity makes him likely to win should he
run. It is easy to dismiss a country whose leader was installed by a waning
military dictatorship, but harder to exclude one whose leader is
democratically elected.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>TWZ  Taiwan, Asia.
    CNZ  China, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9721 International Affairs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 8
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16449</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGEERAARFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940705
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  05 JUL 94 / Issing unworried by M3 rise
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By DAVID WALLER
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   FRANKFURT
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
The current strength of the D-Mark points to investors' confidence in the
Bundesbank monetary policy, Mr Otmar Issing, the German central bank's chief
economist and member of its policy-making council, said yesterday. Mr Issing
blamed the explosion in the growth of M3 money supply since last year on
'special factors' such as tax changes and market turmoil. Following the cut
in the German discount rate in May, circumstances were such that there would
probably be a gradual reduction in the 'liquidity blockage' which had given
rise to the high M3 growth, he said. His comments suggest that the
Bundesbank is not likely to change its reliance on M3 at its July 21 review
of monetary developments, although some economists have cast doubt on the
credibility of the central bank's monetary policy as it has cut interest
rates at a time when M3 growth is running at more than twice its 4-6 per
cent target rate for the year. In May M3 grew at an annualised, seasonally
adjusted rate of 13.7 per cent.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>DEZ  Germany, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9311 Finance, Taxation, and Monetary Policy.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>ECON  Economic Indicators.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 2
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16602</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGDDRAB0FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940704
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  04 JUL 94 / Group to press for 'lookalike' curbs
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By NEIL BUCKLEY
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Representatives of more than 30 leading brand manufacturers will tomorrow
formalise a campaign group to press for legislation curbing supermarkets'
'lookalike' brands, Neil Buckley writes.
The British Producers and Brand Owners Group, set up earlier this year,
failed to get clauses included in the Trademarks Bill to strengthen
restrictions on lookalikes  - own-label products designed to resemble
well-known brands.
The main aim of the group, which includes Unilever, Mars and Nestle, will be
to persuade the government to introduce legislation.
It may also investigate the possibility of taking action against
supermarkets under European Union law.
Own-label products account for more than 50 per cent of sales by volume in
supermarket chains. Brand manufacturers want legislation to stop
supermarkets not only infringing registered trademarks, but copying the
overall look of branded goods, including the colour and shape of packaging.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6794 Patent Owners and Lessors.
    P5411 Grocery Stores.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>MGMT  Management &amp; Marketing.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 8
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16632</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGDDRAA6FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940704
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  04 JUL 94 / Cambodia coup attempt foiled
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By VICTOR MALLET, South East Asia Correspondent
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Cambodia's coalition government announced yesterday that it had foiled an
attempted coup d'etat over the weekend, placing a former interior minister
under house arrest and expelling one of the sons of King Norodom Sihanouk
for plotting the government's overthrow, Victor Mallet, South East Asia
Correspondent, writes.
The attempted coup appears to have been stopped in its early stages without
death or injury, but it demonstrates the fragility of Cambodian democracy a
year after the UN-organised elections.
The authorities detained Mr Sin Song, interior minister under the previous,
communist regime installed by Vietnam, in the early hours of yesterday
morning. They also expelled Prince Chakrapong, a former deputy prime
minister, putting him on a flight to Kuala Lumpur.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>KHZ  Kampuchea, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9199 General Government, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>GOVT  Government News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 4
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16675</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGDDRAFMFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940702
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  02 JUL 94 / World News in Brief: SNP support grows
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Support in Scotland for the Scottish National party is at 30 per cent, its
highest level since 1988, compared to 46 per cent support for Labour,
according to a System Three opinion poll for The Herald.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P8651 Political Organizations.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16710</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGCADAEFFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940702
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  02 JUL 94 / Evolution of long-running cereals: The genetic engineering
of crops that could save the world - The Nature of Things
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By CLIVE COOKSON
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
The last of the dinosaurs grazed on a primeval grass which has since evolved
over 65m years into thousands of different species, including the cereal
crops which together account for more than half the food eaten by mankind.
Today, the different cereals vary enormously in their overall genetic
characteristics. At one extreme is wheat, with a vast amount of genetic
material - six times more DNA than a human being - divided between 21 giant
chromosomes. At the other is rice, which has 12 tiny chromosomes and only
three per cent as much DNA as wheat. In between lie maize, sorghum and
millet.
Research over the past two years has shown, however, that the genes
themselves are remarkably similar in wheat, rice and all other cereals - and
they are arranged in exactly the same sequence in each species. In wheat
(and barley and rye) the genes are interspersed with long repetitive
stretches of 'junk DNA', whereas in rice there is little of this apparently
superfluous DNA which does not control the plant's growth and development.
This surprising discovery, by Mike Gale, Graham Moore and colleagues at
Britain's John Innes Centre in Norwich, working with the Japanese Rice
Genome Research Programme, has huge implications for cereal breeding. It
means that breeders, who have traditionally studied each species separately,
can pool information and quickly come up with a common genetic map that
applies to all grasses and cereals.
Once genes for important characteristics - for example those conferring
resistance to heat or cold, disease or drought - are identified in one
cereal, they can be inserted into another, using the rapidly developing
technology of genetic engineering.
Rice will become the main focus of genetic research in cereals, because its
genome is so much smaller and therefore easier to manipulate than the other
species. (Genome is a useful technical term, meaning all the genetic
material in a species, including the functioning genes, control regions that
switch them on and off, and all the junk DNA in between.) Rice can be used
as a general tool to isolate genes from any cereal crop.
'We will be using rice as a bridge for research on wheat,' says Dick
Flavell, director of the John Innes Centre. 'If I had stood up a few years
ago as head of a British research institute and said we needed to invest in
rice research, people would have thought I was bonkers. But we do need to.'
The latest developments are good news for Japan, which had already decided
to focus its agricultural genetics research on rice. The government-funded
Rice Genome Research Programme, is now half way through the task of
discovering the precise chemical sequence of the estimated 30,000 rice
genes. Fortunately for the rest of the world, the Japanese seem to be
publishing their results quickly and openly, rather than restricting access
or patenting them.
At the same time, plant scientists worldwide are making rapid progress in
developing the genetic engineering technology that will be required to make
practical use of the newly discovered genes.
The 1980s was a frustrating decade because the technique used to transfer
genes to other plants - infecting them with bacteria which carried in the
new DNA - did not work in cereals. But it has turned out during the 1990s
that a brutally direct way of inserting genes - coating thousands of
microscopic gold balls with DNA and firing them into plant cells - is highly
effective.
And earlier this year Zeneca, the British bioscience and seeds company,
announced success with an extraordinarily simple method: the researcher
shakes a test-tube full of water, plant cells, DNA and tiny crystals of a
common chemical called silicon carbide. The crystals (known as whiskers)
punch holes in the cells through which foreign DNA can enter.
The first field trials of genetically engineered wheat, maize and other
cereals are getting under way. Easily traced 'marker genes' have been added
to these plants; they do not confer commercially valuable characteristics
but are used for scientific analysis. In Cambridgeshire, for example, Ciba
Seeds is growing two types of wheat this summer: one has a red pigment gene
taken from wild Peruvian maize and the other produces a bacterial enzyme
that can be detected in simple tests.
In the laboratory, meanwhile, researchers are beginning experiments to
transfer genes that would be industrially useful. The Institute of Arable
Crops Research in the UK has a project, for instance, to give wheat more
genes for gluten proteins, to enhance its bread-making properties.
Another early target might be the genes that control the movement of nitrate
across cell membranes. Their enhancement could help wheat to use nutrients
more efficiently. If so, farmers could cut the amount of nitrate fertilisers
spread on their fields.
In the longer run, there is potentially huge scope for genetic engineering
of all cereals to make them more resistant to attack by pests and diseases
and to withstand adverse weather. But as Paul Lazzeri of the IACR's
Rothamsted Experimental Station points out: 'In parallel with the research,
we have to resolve the question of the public acceptance of genetic
engineering of food.'
Scientists believe that the world will have to accept genetically engineered
cereals. On current projections, twice as much wheat and rice will have to
be produced during the next 50 years as in the past 10,000. Although
improved agronomy can make a contribution, the only real hope for feeding
the growing human population without catastrophic environmental damage lies
in applying cereal genetics.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P8731 Commercial Physical Research.
    P0112 Rice.
    P011  Cash Grains.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page XIII
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16749</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGCADADBFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940702
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  02 JUL 94 / The Lex Column: Nestle
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Equity markets barely stirred at the latest surge in coffee prices. With
around 25 per cent of its profits coming from coffee, Nestle has most at
stake, although Philip Morris - through Kraft General Foods - and Procter &amp;
Gamble also have significant exposures to the brown stuff. Judging by the
steady performance of Nestle shares, investors are taking the view that
manufacturers will have little trouble defending margins despite a 40 per
cent rise in commodity prices.
Past experience certainly gives grounds for confidence. When coffee prices
soared in the mid-1970s and mid-1980s consumers were mostly prepared to
swallow the increase. But in the current price-conscious climate, though,
there is no guarantee that history will repeat itself. Both Philip Morris
and P&amp;G have adopted aggressive pricing strategies in other consumer
markets. Even if consumers are unwilling to pay more this time around,
though, it is difficult to see Nestle being squeezed.
Its strength in instant coffee - where the commodity accounts for only a
small proportion of the retail price - is a competitive advantage. Ground
coffee manufacturers will face greater pressure to raise retail prices.
Although Nestle is coy about the extent of its hedging, it is generally
reckoned to buy more coffee forward than the industry average. And on the
reasonable assumption that as market leader Nestle enjoys higher margins
than most of its competitors, particularly own-label manufacturers, higher
commodity prices could be an opportunity to consolidate its lead.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Nestle.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P0179 Fruits and Tree Nuts, NEC.
    P2095 Roasted Coffee.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
    COSTS  Commodity prices.
    COSTS  Product costs &amp; Product prices.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 24
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16852</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGCADAADFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940702
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  02 JUL 94 / World News in Brief: England take early wickets
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
New Zealand were 84 for four in their first innings on the second day of the
third cricket Test at Old Trafford after dismissing England for 382.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P794  Commercial Sports.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16874</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGAEGAG0FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940701
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  01 JUL 94 / London Stock Exchange: Oil battle blazes
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By PETER JOHN, JOEL KIBAZO and STEVE THOMPSON
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
There was more late drama in the Enterprise Oil/Lasmo takeover battle, with
both camps claiming confidence of success. Significantly, Lasmo shares came
under heavy selling pressure, closing 8 1/2 off at 134 1/2 p on big turnover
of 9.5m, with US investors selling the stock aggressively. Enterprise shares
moved up 7 to 389p.
But contrary to the view that the slide in Lasmo indicated that the bid
would fail, some dealers said US holders were taking the view that an
Enterprise victory was likely. US investors, unwilling to accept the new
Enterprise paper, preferred to sell their shares for cash in the market.
Sector specialists said the bid, the outcome of which is expected minutes
after the market closes today, was still on a knife-edge last night. One
view was that Enterprise had made a tactical blunder in buying half of the
16 per cent held by Philips &amp; Drew Fund Management.
Analysts said that, since PDFM was expected to accept the bid in any event,
Enterprise would have done better to have bid elsewhere for the 10 per cent
stake it sought.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Enterprise Oil.
    LASMO.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P1311 Crude Petroleum and Natural Gas.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 42
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-16996</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGAEGADMFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940701
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  01 JUL 94 / Technology (Worth Watching): Data density with IBM sensor
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By VANESSA HOULDER
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
IBM researchers in San Jose, California have made a highly sensitive sensor
for reading computer data on magnetic hard disks. They believe it will allow
information on disks to be stored nearly 20 times more densely than
currently possible by the turn of the century.
The new sensor, called a 'spin-valve' head, is five times more sensitive
than the disk-drive sensors available now. It is the first high-density
recording head designed to take advantage of the giant magneto-resistive
(GMR) effect, discovered six years ago.
Until recently, all recording heads used electrical induction for reading
and writing data on a disk. The GMR effect, which depends on changes in the
electrical resistance of very thin films of a magnetic material in a
magnetic field, is more sensitive than the induction method for reading
data.
The strength of the signal from the spin-valve allows the disk-drive
designers to reduce the width of the magnetic bit track by six times,
allowing a greater density of data on the bit head. IBM said products
containing 10bn bits of data per square inch of disk surface will be
available by 2000.
IBM: US, 408 927 1283
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3572 Computer Storage Devices.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>TECH  Products &amp; Product use.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 16
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-17008</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGAEGADAFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940701
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  01 JUL 94 / People: Finance moves
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Philip Johnson has been appointed a director of HENRY COOKE Corporate
Finance.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Henry Cooke Corporate Finance.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6799 Investors, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 13
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-17010</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGAEGAC8FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940701
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  01 JUL 94 / People: Finance moves
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Grant Phillips, formerly corporate and institutions group director, has been
appointed md, BARCLAYS investment division of BFS on the retirement of Peter
Dennis.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Barclays.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6021 National Commercial Banks.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 13
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-17019</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGAEGACZFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940701
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  01 JUL 94 / Company failures decline 15%
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
The number of companies failing during the first half of the year fell 15
per cent compared with the first six months of last year, Dun &amp; Bradstreet,
the business-information group, said yesterday.
In the period 21,887 businesses in England and Wales entered liquidation or
receivership which did not lead to the rescue of the company.
The number of failures in Scotland over the same period fell 77 per cent to
1,529, which Dun &amp; Bradstreet said reflected changes to Scottish bankruptcy
regulations.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9611 Administration of General Economic Programs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>ECON  Economic Indicators.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 10
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-17054</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGAEGAB0FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940701
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  01 JUL 94 / London property sold for Pounds 104m
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By ANDREW TAYLOR
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Despa Fonds, a German investment institution, has paid Pounds 104m for the
London headquarters building of retail group John Lewis, Andrew Taylor
writes.
The John Lewis headquarters at 171 Victoria Street was acquired from BfG
Bank of Frankfurt.
The purchase was described by Richard Ellis, commercial estate agents, as
'the biggest West End investment deal for many years'.
It is the second large commercial property purchase to be announced by
German institution in less than a week.
Electricity Supply Nominees, the electricity industry pension fund, on
Monday announced that it had sold for Pounds 106m a City of London office to
Deutsche Immobilien Fonds (DIFA).
The John Lewis headquarters building was constructed in 1975 and has an
unexpired lease of 37 years. The original tenant was BP Oil.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Despa Fonds.
    BfG Bank.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6552 Subdividers and Developers, Ex Cemeteries.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>RES  Facilities.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 8
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-17109</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGAEGAAHFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940701
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  01 JUL 94 / World News in Brief: England in slow start
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
England reached 199 for four on the first day of the third cricket Test
against New Zealand at Old Trafford. England captain Mike Atherton ended
with 96 not out.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P794  Commercial Sports.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-17115</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EGAEGAABFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940701
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  01 JUL 94 / World News in Brief: Opera House redevelopment approved
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
The Royal Opera House in London's Coven Garden was last night granted
planning permission for its Pounds 150m redevelopment scheme.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P7922 Theatrical Producers and Services.
    P9532 Urban and Community Development.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>RES  Facilities.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-1541</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIWEEAEVFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940923
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  23 SEP 94 / International Company News: CRH makes Pounds 14m US purchase
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
CRH, the Dublin-based construction and building materials group, has bought
Rotondo for Dollars 22.5m (Pounds 14.2m) in cash including assumed debt.
Rotondo is the leading supplier of precast concrete enclosures to telephone
and utility companies in the north east of the US. It is also a major
national supplier of precast concrete prison cells.
In the US, CRH's operations are organised under its holding company
Oldcastle, into four core business groups: architectural products,
materials, glass and precast. The Precast Group is a major supplier of
precast telecommunication, utility and environmental products in the Western
and south-eastern US.
Mr Myles Lee, general manager-finance, said the acquisition would extend the
geographical coverage of CRH's precast operations in the US. CRH already had
substantial precast activities in the west and south of the US, but wants to
increase its presence in the north, he said.
Mr Jim Schack, president of the CRH's precast group, said that the synergies
of bringing Rotondo and the Precast Group together involved not only
products and territories, but also the sharing of Rotondo's engineering and
production know-how with the group's other facilities in the US and
internationally.
CRH's shares closed up 3p at 361p.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>CRH.
    Rotondo A and Sons Inc.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>IEZ  Ireland, EC.
    USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3272 Concrete Products, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Mergers &amp; acquisitions.
    MKTS  Market shares.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 26
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-1550</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIWEEAEMFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940923
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  23 SEP 94 / UK Company News: CLS makes Pounds 8.37m at six months
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By SIMON LONDON, Property Correspondent
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
CLS Holdings, the property investment company majority-owned by Sweden's
Mortstedt family, yesterday reported pre-tax profits of Pounds 8.37m in the
first half of 1994, compared with a loss of Pounds 1.49m last time.
Excluding exceptional items, though, the company's first set of figures
since making its stock exchange debut in May showed a profit before tax from
continuing operations of Pounds 1.95m, against Pounds 575,000 before.
After adjusting for transactions completed since flotation, net assets per
share were 129p.
The first interim dividend is 0.4p, although the Mortstedt family, who own
53 per cent of the shares, have agreed to take a scrip alternative.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>CLS Holdings.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6552 Subdividers and Developers, Ex Cemeteries.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>FIN  Interim results.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 24
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-1619</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIWEEACPFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940923
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  23 SEP 94 / Peugeot invests Pounds 30m in Ryton plant
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By JOHN GRIFFITHS
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Peugeot Talbot is to spend around Pounds 30m to start production of a saloon
version of the Peugeot 306 hatchback early next year at its Ryton plant near
Coventry.
The company said yesterday that the plant's output was to be increased from
1,820 cars a week to 2,000 cars a week from January creating 'several
hundred' new jobs among Peugeot Talbot's 70 component suppliers. The
government is providing Pounds 1.2m in grants for the expansion.
Peugeot Talbot, UK production and distribution subsidiary of the French
vehicles group, expects the additional cars to lift Ryton's total output
from 73,000 this year to approaching 90,000 in 1995 and return the company
to profitability. Last year Peugeot Talbot made its first loss since the
late 1980s - Pounds 8.7m before tax.
Mr Geoffrey Whalen, Peugeot Talbot deputy chairman, said there was little
early prospect of more jobs at the Ryton plant itself, which employs 3,000
people. This is because it has maintained double-shift working - with
downtime and temporary lay-offs - in spite of the slump in UK and
continental European markets which caused Ryton's output to fall from a peak
116,000 units in 1990.
By keeping the workforce intact, Ryton retains its capacity to make 120,000
cars a year.
Even with the saloon 306, Ryton is unlikely to be utilising its full
capacity unless export demand for both 306 models expands considerably.
Mr Whalen said there were no plans to reintroduce the larger 405 saloon - or
its successor to be launched in France next year - to Ryton's assembly lines
alongside the 306 models. The 405, a big success in the UK fleet market,
accounted for most of Ryton's production until the Continental market slump
led Peugeot to confine 405 output to France at the end of 1992.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Peugeot Talbot Motor.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3711 Motor Vehicles and Car Bodies.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>RES  Capital expenditures.
    MKTS  Production.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 10
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-1701</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIWEEAAEFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940923
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  23 SEP 94 / World News in Brief: Soldiers killed in helicopter crash
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Two British soldiers were killed when their Lynx military helicopter crashed
during an exercise in Germany, near the Moselle river.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>DEZ  Germany, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9229 Public Order and Safety, NEC.
    P9711 National Security.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-1802</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIVD2AD9FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940922
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  22 SEP 94 / Observer: No idea
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
The effervescent Janet Street-Porter is leaving the BBC, where she has been
head of independent television production in the entertainment field, to
join the Mirror Group, where she will be managing director of a new cable
network. 'I regret leaving a place where ideas are paramount,' she said
yesterday. The very idea that ideas may not be paramount at her new employer
seems to be one worth pursuing . . .
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Mirror Group.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P4841 Cable and Other Pay Television Services.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 23
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-1829</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIVD2ADIFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940922
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  22 SEP 94 / People: Downing emerges at Lehman
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
David Gilchrist has been promoted to group secretary of the HALIFAX BUILDING
SOCIETY.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Halifax Building Society.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6162 Mortgage Bankers and Correspondents.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 20
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-1831</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIVD2ADGFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940922
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  22 SEP 94 / People: Non-executive directors
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Simon Miller, chairman of Safetynet and Ferrum Holdings, as chairman of
DUNEDIN VENTURES.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Dunedin Ventures.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6726 Investment Offices, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 20
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-1833</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIVD2ADEFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940922
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  22 SEP 94 / People: Non-executive directors
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Laurie Conner, 57, a former managing director of corporate finance at Hoare
Govett, and Lionel Barras, 62, an investment banker, at Guinness Mahon &amp; Co.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Guinness Mahon and Co.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6029 Commercial Banks, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 20
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-1914</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIVD2AA5FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940922
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  22 SEP 94 / German recovery 'to gather pace'
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By ANDREW FISHER
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   FRANKFURT
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
German economic growth was forecast yesterday to speed up next year after
this year's faster than expected recovery from recession.
The optimistic predictions by the government, just ahead of the October 16
federal elections, coincided with the release of data showing a
slower-than-expected growth in August money supply.
Mr Gunter Rexrodt, the economics minister, told parliament the government
expected the economy to grow by 3 per cent in 1995. For this year he
estimated that expansion would reach 2.5 per cent instead of a previously
projected 2.25 per cent.
His comments came in a strongly political speech ahead of the election, in
which he set the government's economic record against the policies of the
Social Democrat opposition. The minister also forecast that unemployment
would fall by 200,000 next year. The Bundesbank announced a much slower
annualised growth rate for M3 money supply of 8.2 per cent in August. It
reaffirmed its intention to keep a firm hand on monetary policy to secure
steady economic growth and lower inflation.
With the economy recovering speedily, the Bundesbank is concerned to prevent
consumer prices from accelerating.
Before the Bundesbank's announcement, financial markets were concerned that
the expansion rate of money supply might again have exceeded 9 per cent. In
July, the annualised growth rate for M3 was 9.8 per cent; in May, it reached
15.4 per cent.
In spite of the success of the central bank in bringing down money supply
growth, Mr Johan Wilhelm Gaddum, Bundesbank deputy president, said it was
still concerned about inflation.
In August, west German inflation was 3 per cent, compared with the
Bundesbank's eventual goal of 2 per cent. Mr Gaddum said the price outlook
had improved now that fiscal and wage trends were moving in a more moderate
direction. 'Yet the progress towards stability still does not mean it is
time to sound the all clear.'
That reaffirmation of the Bundesbank's anti-inflationary stance, and the
emphasis on its continued commitment to money supply targets, has led some
economists to conclude that it is unlikely to cut interest rates further.
Others, however, expect a further cut after the election. The last reduction
was in May, when the discount and Lombard rates were cut to 4.5 per cent and
6 per cent respectively.
Mr Gaddum indicated last week that there was no reason to cut rates now. The
May cuts were aimed at shifting funds from short-term deposits, which show
up in M3, to longer-term investments, which do not. Mr Gaddum added
yesterday that the Bundesbank was confident the M3 rate would continue
falling towards the 1994 target range of 4 per cent to 6 per cent.
Lex, Page 24
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>DEZ  Germany, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9311 Finance, Taxation, and Monetary Policy.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>ECON  Economic Indicators.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 2
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-1933</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIVD2AAMFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940922
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  22 SEP 94 / Growth of German money slows
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By ANDREW FISHER
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   FRANKFURT
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Germany's money supply grew at a much lower than expected annual rate of 8.2
per cent in August, but the Bundesbank made clear yesterday it would keep a
firm hand on monetary policy to secure steady economic growth and lower
inflation.
With the economy recovering speedily, the Bundesbank is concerned to prevent
consumer prices from accelerating. In a speech made with next month's
general election strongly in mind, Mr Gunter Rexrodt, the economics
minister, forecast an economic growth rate for 1995 of 3 per cent after 2.5
per cent this year. He also said unemployment would fall by 200,000 jobs
next year.
Before the Bundesbank's M3 announcement, financial markets had been nervous
that the expansion rate of money supply might again have exceeded 9 per
cent. German bond prices fell sharply on Tuesday on such concerns. In July,
the annualised growth rate for M3 was 9.8 per cent; in May, it was still as
high as 15.4 per cent.
Despite the success in bringing down money supply growth, however, Mr Johan
Wilhelm Gaddum, the Bundesbank's deputy president, said it was still
concerned about inflation. 'We cannot be satisfied with the present rate of
price increase.'
In August, the west German inflation rate was 3 per cent compared with the
Bundesbank's goal of 2 per cent. Mr Gaddum said the price outlook had
improved now that fiscal and wage trends were moving in a more moderate
direction. 'Yet the progress towards stability still does not mean it is
time to sound the all clear in the battle against inflation.'
This reaffirmation of the Bundesbank's anti-inflationary stance, and the
stressing of its continued commitment to money supply targets, has led some
economists to conclude it is unlikely to cut interest rates further. Others,
though, expect one more cut after the election. The last reduction was in
May when the discount and Lombard rates were cut to 4.5 and 6 per cent
respectively.
Mr Gaddum indicated last week there was no reason to cut rates now. The May
cuts were aimed at shifting funds from short-term deposits, which show up in
M3, to longer-term investments, which do not. This move helped reduce money
supply growth and Mr Gaddum added yesterday that the Bundesbank was
confident the M3 rate would continue falling towards the 1994 target range
of between 4 and 6 per cent.
The Bundesbank said one reason for lower M3 growth in August was a switch of
funds from short-term deposits to Luxembourg-based money market funds
offering slightly higher yields. Money market funds, allowed in Germany
since August, are not part of M3; about 20 such funds, registered in both
Luxembourg and Germany, have either been set up or are awaiting approval.
Lex, Page 24
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>DEZ  Germany, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9311 Finance, Taxation, and Monetary Policy.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>ECON  Economic Indicators.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 2
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-2065</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIUDKADKFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940921
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  21 SEP 94 / Observer: Two plus two
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Back to bankers, and a question as to how many varieties of the species
there are? Why, three of course. Those who can count and those who can't.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P99   Nonclassifiable Establishments.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 21
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-2094</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIUDKACRFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940921
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  21 SEP 94 / People: Non-executive directors
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
David Heywood as chairman of QS HOLDINGS.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>QS Holdings.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P5651 Family Clothing Stores.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 17
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-2131</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIUDKABPFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940921
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  21 SEP 94 / Adams may meet Congress members
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By GEORGE GRAHAM
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   WASHINGTON
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Mr Gerry Adams, head of Sinn Fein, is expected to meet members of both
houses of the US Congress when he visits Washington next month. Mr Adams
yesterday applied for a US visa, George Graham in Washington writes.
Although congressional committees traditionally do not hold full hearings
for foreign visitors, Mr Adams is expected to meet members of the Senate
foreign relations committee for a 'committee coffee', and meetings are also
likely with members of the House of Representatives.
Other leading Northern Irish politicians have also been beating a path to
Congress's door. Mr John Hume was due to meet senators yesterday afternoon,
and a delegation of Ulster Unionists is to arrive in Washington today.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P8651 Political Organizations.
    P9121 Legislative Bodies.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 8
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-2175</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIUDKAAHFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940921
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  21 SEP 94 / World News in Brief: Jule Styne dies
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
British-born Jule Styne, who wrote the scores for Broadway shows such as
Gentlemen Prefer Blondes and Funny Girl, and 1,500 songs including Three
Coins in the Fountain, died in New York aged 88.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P99   Nonclassifiable Establishments.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  People.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-2207</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIUAHABBFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940920
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  20 SEP 94 / UK Company News: YRM
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
YRM, the building design company, was continuing to discuss possibility of
refinancing, Mr Tim Poulson, chief executive, told AGM. He said year-end
figures of April 30, which showed a trading loss in an 'extremely difficult'
year, did not show company was enjoying a 'steady influx' of new business
from UK and abroad.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>YRM.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P8711 Engineering Services.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>FIN  Annual report.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 24
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-2211</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIUAHAA7FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940920
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  20 SEP 94 / UK Company News: Allied-Lyons
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
ALLIED-LYONS yesterday changed its name to Allied Domecq.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Allied-Lyons.
    Allied Domecq.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P2085 Distilled and Blended Liquors.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Company News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 24
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-2281</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EITEUADYFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940920
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  20 SEP 94 / International Company News: Court throws out Apple
copyrights lawsuit
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By LOUISE KEHOE
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   SAN FRANCISCO
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
On the heels of Apple Computer's decision to license its proprietary
Macintosh personal computer operating system software to other PC companies,
a California appeals court has thrown out Apple's charges that Microsoft's
competing Windows PC operating system, and related software from
Hewlett-Packard, infringe Apple copyrights.
The copyright infringement suit, filed six years ago, was part of Apple's
efforts in the past to protect the 'look and feel' of the Macintosh software
which - until the introduction of Microsoft's Windows in 1987 - gave Apple a
competitive advantage over IBM and other PC makers.
That advantage has long since been lost, with Microsoft's Windows now the
standard operating system for all IBM-compatible PCs. However, by licensing
its software to other PC manufacturers, Apple hopes to regain lost ground.
Initially, Apple will license its core Mac OS and elements of its PowerPC
hardware design which until now have been unique to its own products, to
companies that are not direct competitors in markets where Apple has limited
distribution and in specialised market segments. The company said 'over
time' it aims to license its technology more broadly.
Already 'about six companies' have signed licensing agreements, Apple said,
but refused to identify the licensees other than to say that they are
equally divided among the US, Europe and Asia. The first Macintosh-style
products from third parties are expected to be introduced by late 1995.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Apple Computer Inc.
    Microsoft Corp.
    Hewlett-Packard Co Inc.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9211 Courts.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>TECH  Patents &amp; Licences.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 28
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-2340</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EITEUACAFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940920
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  20 SEP 94 / N Herts MP made Waldegrave aide
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Mr Oliver Heald, Conservative MP for North Hertfordshire, was yesterday
appointed parliamentary private secretary to Mr William Waldegrave,
agriculture minister.
Mr Heald was elected in April 1992. He was previously parliamentary private
secretary to Mr Peter Lloyd, the former Home Office minister.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9199 General Government, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 11
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-2450</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EISF8AEVFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940919
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  19 SEP 94 / Emerging Markets: News round-up - Strategy
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By REUTER
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Baring Securities has forecast that the remainder of 1994 and 1995 should
see an upturn in emerging markets with institutional funds being switched
from south-east Asia to Latin America, Reuter reports.
Barings remarked that the main propellant of emerging markets strategy was
the US economy. If US growth was slow bonds were likely to rally, providing
an incentive to invest in south-east Asia. 'But with a strong US economy
Latin America historically performs better, pushed along by pressure on
commodity prices,' said Barings. A mediocre performance from the US economy,
however, should drive funds to Japan and north-east Asia.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>JPZ  Japan, Asia.
    XOZ  Asia.
    XCZ  Latin America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9311 Finance, Taxation, and Monetary Policy.
    P6231 Security and Commodity Exchanges.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 29
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-2479</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EISF8AD0FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940919
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  19 SEP 94 / Company News (This Week): RMC - Other Companies
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
The world's biggest concrete company reports half-year figures on Thursday.
Forecasts suggest pre-tax profits of just over Pounds 90m compared with
Pounds 61.6m in the first half of 1993.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>RMC Group.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3273 Ready-Mixed Concrete.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 25
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-2630</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIRAQAFQFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940917
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  17 SEP 94 / Food &amp; Drink: Great British Eating sites
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
ENGLISH HERITAGE
Pevensey Castle Cottage Tea Rooms &amp; Restaurant, near Eastbourne, Sussex. The
Brew House at the Iveagh Bequest, Kenwood House, Hampstead, London. The
Coach House Cafe at Marble Hall house and park, Twickenham, Middlesex. The
Tea Room at Audley End house, near Saffron Walden, Cambridgeshire. Osborne
House, Cowes, Isle of Wight.
NATIONAL TRUST
Hardwick Hall, Doe Lea, Chesterfield, Derbyshire. Souter lighthouse,
Whitburn, Sunderland, Tyne &amp; Wear. Wordsworth House, Cockermouth, Cumbria,
Sissinghurst Garden, Sissinghurst, Kent. St Michael's Mount, Marazion, near
Penzance, Cornwall.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P5812 Eating Places.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page XX
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-2672</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIRAQAEJFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940917
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  17 SEP 94 / Travel: Paddleboat pampering on Big Muddy - Christina Lamb
cruised part of the Mississippi on the Delta Queen, an historic steamboat
fitted out like a floating palace
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By CHRISTINA LAMB
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
It takes just one blow of a steamboat whistle on the quay at New Orleans to
find yourself transported into the storybook past of the Mississippi
paddleboats. Like multi-tiered wedding cakes, they churned the muddy waters
with their giant wheels, transporting men in Sunday suits and women in
be-ribboned bonnets towards their dreams.
The Delta Queen is about to set off. The great red wheel starts churning and
a top-hatted man on deck taps out a reedy version of 'Toot toot tootsie,
goodbye' on the calliope (or steam organ), sending puffs of smoke out of its
shining brass pipes.
In Life on the Mississippi, Mark Twain wrote that it was every boy's
ambition to be a steamboat man. Generations of children brought up on his
books have fantasised about running away from home and following in
Huckleberry Finn's footsteps along the great, brown river.
For a not entirely modest sum, the Delta Queen Steamboat Company offers the
chance to slip away from modern-day stresses and live out that fantasy on
one of its two paddle-wheel steamboats. Some people prefer the Mississippi
Queen with such modern amenities as cinema and pool. But, for romantics,
there is no choice but its elderly relative, the Delta Queen.
Now in its 68th year of operations, the Delta Queen is the oldest steamboat
in the world offering cruises, and has been declared a US national historic
landmark. It is like a floating palace with teak-panelled state-rooms, brass
fittings and Tiffany-style stained glass. As a result, it is easy to imagine
the days when silk-clad ladies sat doing embroidery while the men played
poker in the for'ard bar.
The Delta Queen runs tours of between three and 12 days through America's
heartland. Wanting to do things properly, I opted for one called 'The Old
South', which promised to 'recapture the ambience and history of this
gracious way of life'.
The scenery on the 682-mile round trip from New Orleans to Vicksburg, on the
lower Mississippi, is disappointing. Known as the chemical corridor, the
banks are lined with refineries and petro-chemical plants spewing out yellow
smoke and thick oily globules. But you do not take a trip like this for the
sights.
Nor for the excitement. Progress is so stately that the boat is often
overtaken by cyclists. Fellow passengers tend to be over 65 and like wearing
name tags. For those who do not relish playing bingo or dressing up for
floozie parades, day-time activities consist of reading the daily
Steamboatin' Times and flying kites (which usually end up tangled in the
wheel).
Nights in the bar are spent listening to the quavery crooning of the
ever-smiling Charlotte Champagne or dancing in the Orleans room, where
tireless Bob Schad is a whizz on the banjo. But even the most energetic soon
settle into the slow rhythm on-board, punctuated by occasional sightseeing
stops and frequent large meals of local delicacies such as alligator and
catfish.
The main pastime is river-watching from one of the rocking chairs on deck.
TS Eliot called the Mississippi 'a great brown god', and it captivates
quickly. On waking in the mornings, we could see it at its most mysterious,
swathed in a low mist from which the tops of submerged trees poked through.
At night, under the silvery glow of a full harvest moon, it was almost
beautiful. But it was at its most soulful during the day, the Delta Queen
nosing through thick, chocolate-brown water which even the US Army Corps of
Engineers cannot control as, flush with spring rains, it changes course and
bursts banks to show that it is not to be messed with.
Known as Big Muddy, the Mississippi is the longest river in the US, draining
all or part of 31 states on its winding, 2,500-mile journey from the hills
of Minnesota to the Gulf of Mexico. It is also America's hardest-working
waterway, carrying 500m tons of cargo each year in enormous, snaking lines
of connected barges. These, as long as five football fields, tend to take up
the whole river as they round bends.
There is so much traffic that the Delta Queen's jovial Captain John Davitt
compares the river to 'driving on an interstate highway'. But while motorway
drivers may go faster than 7mph, they do not have sandbanks and floating
logs to contend with. Avoiding these obstacles, and the barges, requires
great skill from the river pilots who drive the steamboats. And becoming a
pilot is not easy: the licence is granted in 20-mile segments and those
applying have to draw, from memory, every turn of the river, sandbar, bridge
and buoy in that stretch.
The Delta Queen's stops are orchestrated to shield passengers from contact
with the 1990s, although it is hard to avoid the tin-roofed slums and
proliferation of riverboat casinos (to which many of the crew slip off).
On our first morning we moored at Oak Alley, a Greek revival-style,
antebellum plantation house painted candy pink and reached through a grass
alley of 300-year-old oaks so gnarled that the branches touch the floor and
meet overhead to make an archway. Inside the drawing room, a painted wooden
screen stands in front of the fire; it used to prevent beeswax make-up,
layered on to cover smallpox scars, melting into the ladies' laps.
Our next stops were St Francisville, a pretty town under a veil of Spanish
moss, and Natchez, home to more than half the country's millionaires in the
1850s. Louisiana was the centre of the plantation economy and the lower
Mississippi area is dotted with large, colonnaded houses, built mostly
between the late 18th century and the civil war to show off the wealth
generated by cotton, indigo, rice and sugar.
Every year, during March, many of these private mansions are opened to the
public to show off opulent (and often tasteless) interiors, plus gardens
resplendent with magnolia and dog rose blossoms. Their lavish settings, and
names like Rosedown or Nottoway, inspire romantic images of crinolined
belles and dashing beaux with waxed moustaches.
Finally, we came to Vicksburg, which is positioned on a steep bluff
overlooking the river. During the civil war it was a Confederate stronghold
defending the whole of the lower Mississippi. In May 1863, General Grant's
army marched on the town; when the Confederates refused to surrender, he
ordered his army to starve them out. The bloody siege lasted 47 days. Now,
in the immaculately-kept Battleground Park, the old cannons still point at
each other while red and blue markers show where the Yankee and rebel troops
fought.
Each stop we made was marked by a huge puff of steam and a frenzy of
calliope-playing. Locals or camera-toting tourists gathered on shore to wave
us off, recalling the 'Steamboat a' comin]' days of last century when
paddle-wheelers like this used to rule the river.
The Delta Queen was built in a Glasgow shipyard in the 1920s for the
Californian Transportation Co. Its owners poured Dollars 875,000 into
creating a four-tiered, balustraded beauty. Used initially as an overnight
dinner cruiser between Sacramento and San Francisco, the depression forced
its withdrawal from service until Pearl Harbour. Then, it was requisitioned
by the navy, painted grey and used as a troop transporter.
Since then, the Delta Queen has passed through various owners and overhauls.
It even survived congressional legislation passed to prevent the operation
of wooden boats after a tragic fire on a cruise-liner.
The most spectacular part of the boat is the engine room. Passengers are
welcome to see the pistons driving a 40ft-long Pitman arm connected to a
crankshaft which turns the 44-ton paddle wheel.
Every so often on steamboats, pressure from the boilers gets so high that it
has to be relieved through a safety valve - the origin of the expression
'letting off steam'. After a week being pampered on the Delta Queen, I can
think of no better place to do that.
Christina Lamb travelled with the Delta Queen Steamboat Co of 30 Robin
Street Wharf, New Orleans. Information: tel (800)-543 1949.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P7999 Amusement and Recreation, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page XI
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-2776</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIRAQABMFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940917
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  17 SEP 94 / Diseased turbot will be culled
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By JAMES BUXTON, Scottish Correspondent
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Thousands of turbot at an experimental fish farm on the island of Gigha, off
the coast of Argyll, are to be killed after government officials confirmed
they were suffering from a fish disease which has not been recorded in the
British Isles before.
The fish are affected with viral haemorrhagic septicaemia (VHS), a disease
which UK and European Union legislation requires to be eradicated if its
breaks out. The disease is said to be endemic on the Continent.
The affected fish farm has been placed under quarantine for killing and
clearance, and movement of fish from a salmon farm on the island has been
banned.
The disease was discovered last week at the turbot farm which is owned by
the McConnell Salmon company. Its confirmation as VHS has alarmed fish
farmers in Scotland, who fear that they could be affected by the disease or
suffer from bad publicity.
The Ministry of Agriculture says VHS can affect salmon, rainbow trout, brown
trout, grayling and other species.
However, Mr David Windmill, managing director of McConnell Salmon, said the
company had found no evidence in the scientific literature of VHS affecting
salmon, which make up the majority of fish farmed in Scotland.
Mr Seumas McSporran, sub-postmaster on Gigha, which has a population of 120,
said: 'It would be a crisis for us if both the fish farms had to close.'
The turbot farm, which has been operating for a year in its present form,
contains about 200,000 turbot, worth about Pounds 500,000. McConnell Salmon
started the operation to see whether turbot could be farmed as successfully
as salmon.
Mr Windmill thought the disease could have reached the fish through their
moist feed.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>McConnell Salmon.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P0273 Animal Aquaculture.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Company News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 7
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-2912</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIPC9AD9FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940916
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  16 SEP 94 / UK Company News: Liberty Mutual to invest in Lloyd's
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By RICHARD LAPPER
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Liberty Mutual, a US insurance company, is to invest in Lloyd's of London,
signalling continuing interest by corporate investors in the market.
The news coincided with the publication by Lloyd's of new rules which allow
corporate members greater room for manoeuvre. The market, which won some
Pounds 800m in corporate investment last year, is hoping to attract a
further Pounds 125m to Pounds 250m in 1995.
Liberty, a Boston-based group, said its investment would allow Cater Allen
Syndicate Management, an agency part of Cater Allen Holdings, to provide an
extra Pounds 40m in capacity to Syndicate 190, increasing its potential
premium income to more than Pounds 70m next year.
Management of the syndicate, will switch to a new agency next year, although
this is dependent on the approval of the regulatory authorities at Lloyd's.
'These arrangements reflect both Lloyd's stated aims of broadening the
market's capital base and the recent trend towards corporate capital at
Lloyd's being provided on a dedicated basis to selected syndicates,' said Mr
Robin Gilkes, chairman of Cater Allen Syndicate Management.
Separately Lloyd's announced that corporate syndicates - ones which contain
one member whose sole business is writing on that syndicate - will be
permitted next year. So-called 'parallel syndicates', which will underwrite
business alongside existing syndicates, will also be permitted.
Other changes will allow corporate members to own up to 25 per cent of the
agents which administer syndicates. New rules governing the conditions under
which corporate member groups can acquire up to 100 per cent of managing
agents will be published by the middle of next year.
Lloyd's also said that it would slow the planned introduction of
'assignment', a principle allowing Names to trade or transfer their
participations on syndicates. The only form of assignment likely to be
introduced in 1995 will be for Names re-arranging their affairs through
Mapas, a kind of Lloyd's unit trust, or a new kind of limited liability
corporate vehicle, which is under consideration at the market.
Existing rules, which limit corporate member groups to 50 per cent of a
single syndicate's capacity, and any one corporate member to no more than 25
per cent, will be waived 'only if managing agents demonstrate that
individual members' pre-emption and other rights have not been ignored'.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Liberty Mutual Insurance.
    Lloyd's of London.
    Cater Allen Syndicate Management.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>USZ  United States of America.
    GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6411 Insurance Agents, Brokers, and Service.
    P6331 Fire, Marine, and Casualty Insurance.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Company News.
    RES  Capital expenditures.
    TECH  Safety &amp; Standards.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 20
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-2971</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIPC9ACMFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940916
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  16 SEP 94 / Management: Getting to grips with a killer disease - The
incidence of testicular cancer has doubled over the last 20 years
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By CAROL COOPER
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
When asked to name the commonest cancer in men under 45, most people get it
wrong, I concluded at a recent dinner party. My question killed the
conversation dead, but it highlighted the importance of testicular cancer.
One man in 450 will develop this cancer before the age of 50 and more than
1,400 new cases are diagnosed in the UK every year. The incidence is even
higher in other northern European countries, notably Denmark, Germany,
Switzerland, Ireland and Luxembourg.
Testicular cancer is generally treated with a combination of surgery and
chemotherapy, with great success. (Sterility is the rule for a year or two
after treatment, but the long-term outlook is excellent.) Around 95 per cent
recover completely and many father children. Unfortunately, results are less
good when the disease is advanced. In 1992, this cancer killed 123 men in
England and Wales.
Few men examine themselves regularly - only 3 per cent, according to an
Imperial Cancer Research Fund (ICRF) study. As for breast disease, the value
of self-examination is disputed, but many authorities now recommend it on
the basis that it is important to be familiar with one's own anatomy.
Signs to be taken seriously include swelling of one testicle, or a lump on
the front or side. Sometimes there is real pain, but often there are only
vague symptoms such as dull ache, heaviness, or change in feel.
Unfortunately, men are reluctant to go to the doctor and may have to be
propelled into the surgery by wife or girlfriend. Many men, perhaps
believing that the symptoms will go away, leave things too late - over half
of all those with testicular cancer seek help after the tumour has spread.
This cancer does not spread to the easily felt lymph glands in the groin,
but to those around the aorta, deep within the abdomen. This is entirely
logical given that the testicle originates embryologically from that area.
In the past 20 years, the incidence of testicular cancer has doubled. It is
rising, especially in younger white men and in higher social classes, for
reasons which are unclear. Nobody knows the cause of testicular cancer, but
risk factors are coming to light.
Until recently, an undescended or partly descended testis was one of the few
known causal factors. If left surgically uncorrected beyond the age of 10 or
so, this condition roughly trebles the risk of testicular cancer - even on
the side which appears normal.
Heredity appears to be even more important and a history of this cancer in a
close relative calls for extra vigilance. Sons of men with the disease are
four times as likely to develop it, while brothers of those affected are
nearly 10 times as likely to do so.
In the hope of finding a gene for it, a research project is now being
carried out into families with two or more members with testicular cancer.
Sixty such families have been identified so far in Britain and the Cancer
Research Campaign (CRC) and ICRF are on the lookout for more.
Over the years, there have been worries about the possible effect of mumps,
vasectomy, injury and heat (especially in the form of tight trousers, hot
baths and central heating).
A leading study from the UK Testicular Cancer Study Group looked into the
medical and social histories of nearly 800 men with the disease in nine
British health regions. The findings were reported in May in the British
Medical Journal and this month in the British Journal of Cancer.
There seems to be no association between testicular cancer and either heat
or mumps (even after puberty, when orchitis, as it is known, is more
likely). But a history of any sexually transmitted disease appears to double
the risk of this cancer. There is also some relation between infertility and
testicular cancer, but it is not yet clear whether this is cause-and-effect.
Men contemplating vasectomy, however, should be reassured - there is no
evidence of a link.
The study suggests that regular exercise could have a protective effect  -
men who exercise for 15 or more hours a week had a substantially lower
incidence. But injury to the testis can double the risk. This could be
significant in some sports, although there are not yet enough data on which
to base firm advice.
Finally, there is some suggestion that an early puberty is an important risk
factor. This ties in with the theory that high levels of gonadotrophin
hormones from the pituitary gland may stimulate cells in such a way as to
promote cancerous change. And since puberty is occurring earlier these days,
often well before the standard age of 14 in boys, it is also consistent with
the rising trend in testicular cancer. However, there is unlikely to be a
single cause for this cancer or, put another way, one remains to be
discovered.
For more information about testicular cancer, contact ICRF, PO Box 123,
Lincoln's Inn Fields, London WC2A 3FX. Tel 071 242 0200.
The author is a London general practitioner.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9431 Administration of Public Health Programs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 12
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT943-3089</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EIOC7AGGFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>940915
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  15 SEP 94 / International Company News: Advance for Indonesian timber
group
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By MANUELA SARAGOSA
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   JAKARTA
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
PT Barito Pacific Timber, Indonesia's largest manufacturer of timber
products, said net income in the first six months of 1994 rose to Rp103bn
(Dollars 47m) from Rp82bn a year earlier.
The company also reported that net sales increased to Rp481bn from Rp462bn
the year before.
Barito Pacific has come under fire recently for management at its forest
concessions.
The company, which ranks as the world's largest tropical hardwood plywood
manufacturer, is majority owned by Mr Prajogo Pangestu.
Mr Pangestu recently agreed to allow the Indonesian government to take a 49
per cent stake in two of the forest concessions he operates and which supply
Barito Pacific with timber.
The Ministry of Forestry said that the move was aimed at improving
management at the forest concessions.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>PT Barito Pacific Timber.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>IDZ  Indonesia, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P2435 Hardwood Veneer and Plywood.
    P2499 Wood Products, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>FIN  Interim results.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 28
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-FABCLAD7FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941231
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  31 DEC 94 / N Korea 'brought down' US helicopter
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By JOHN BURTON, Seoul Correspondent, and Agencies
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
US army pilot Bobby Hall, in his first debriefing by US officials since
being freed by North Korea, said his helicopter was hit by air defences
after it strayed across the border, forcing him into an emergency landing.
Chief Warrant Officer Hall reported that after he brought the craft to the
ground, he pulled his gravely wounded co-pilot, Chief Warrant Officer David
Hilemon, from the aircraft, according to a US government official.
Mr Hall told officials that Mr Hilemon died a short time later, the official
said.
At the time of the shooting-down, Mr Hall thought he was over South Korea
and apparently did not realise his helicopter had been struck and that Mr
Hilemon had been hit, the official said.
Mr Hall said he was well treated in captivity, the official said.
North Korea yesterday returned Mr Hall yesterday. His release appeared to
ensure that the recent US-North Korean nuclear agreement will proceed
smoothly after Washington warned earlier that his continued detention could
jeopardise the accord.
The US is 'pleased that we can now look to the future and implement the
important project', said Mr Thomas Hubbard, deputy assistant secretary of
state, who spent two 'difficult' days in Pyongyang negotiating Mr Hall's
release.
Under the nuclear accord, the US has promised to establish diplomatic ties
with North Korea and guarantee international aid if Pyongyang abandons its
nuclear programme.
The return of Mr Hall was the result of a diplomatic compromise.
The US expressed regret for the intrusion of the helicopter into North
Korean airspace, which Washington said was an accident caused by a
navigational error.
The US did not offer a formal apology as demanded by North Korea, which
claimed the helicopter was on a spy mission.
However, North Korea appeared satisfied by a 'confession' signed by Mr Hall,
which described the 'illegal intrusion' as a 'criminal action' and asked for
forgiveness by Pyongyang.
North Korea claimed the US had agreed to further bilateral military contacts
to prevent future incidents. But Mr Hubbard denied that the US had given
such commitments.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>KPZ  North Korea, Asia.
    USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9721 International Affairs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 3
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-17</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-FAAACAEOFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941231
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  31 DEC 94 / Outdoors: King Cone looks for new roads to conquer -
Motoring / Simon Hughes meets a man who just loves roadworks
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By SIMON HUGHES
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
In the interests of safety an ordinary motorway contra-flow requires about
10,000 road cones. In view of the number of roads currently under repair
this means there are probably more than 3m cones in use in Britain alone.
'By the year 2000,' the Highways Agency forecasts, '37 per cent of Britain's
motorway network could be operating above its design capacity.' In other
words, over a third of its main roads will be either blocked with cars or
coned off for repair. We are moving into the era of King Cone.
In the Gloucestershire hamlet of Broughton Poggs this news is cause for
optimism. Broughton Poggs is the home of Peter Cook Safety Products, the
world's leading producer of cones - every week they make 25,000 of them.
David Morgan, the company's managing director and inventor of the plastic
cone even collects them. He has 570 in his garage.
Morgan produced the first PVC cone in 1967 while he was working at ICI and
experimenting with liquid polythene.
'It was my job to make products using a rotating moulding machine. I tried
designing hollow toys - one was an elephant but when I pulled it out of the
mould the trunk kept breaking off. I drove over a wooden police cone going
to work one day and realised it was the perfect shape for my machine.'
In 1973 he was invited to set up a cone manufacturing plant for British
Telecom and he has been making and collecting them ever since.
Morgan was runner-up in a recent British television vote for the most boring
man in Britain (the winner collected brown paper bags). But how could anyone
want to surround himself with objects that symbolise danger and
frustra-tion?
'For me road cones hold an extraordinary fascination, and I can spot a
different design at 100 yards,' he says. 'I search for different styles
everywhere I travel, and then barter for new discoveries with swaps in my
boot.'
The prizes in his collection include a five-sided cone he picked up in
Manchester, a Malaysian version he found on a beach in the Scilly Isles, and
one from his own company which floated ashore while he was on holiday in
Corsica.
'I took it through the red channel at Heathrow customs but the man said: 'We
haven't got a category for that. OK, carry on.''
The adaptability of these coloured plastic sentries is immense. They turn up
guarding wet paint or washed floors in public buildings, on football
training grounds or at cycling proficiency test centres, as accessories in
student bedsits, and as chewable toys for young pit bull terriers. Morgan
spotted one suspended over a naked bulb outside a brothel in Amsterdam.
And he recently received a video from a zoo-keeper of a polar bear playing
with one - swimming with it and storing his food in it.
'Watch News at Ten every day and there'll always be one of mine somewhere,'
he says.
They possess great authority. Motorists manoeuvre obediently around them
even when they have strayed from their original position. The key is to keep
them upright - a horizontal cone is usually ignored - and for this reason a
legion of workers pour 20 tons of sand a day into the black-plastic base.
Morgan has done well from the cones. He runs a highly successful 24-hour
manufacturing business with a Pounds 9m turnover.
Britain, with the best road safety record in the world, has persuaded other
countries to invest in cones and 20 per cent of their sales are overseas,
mostly to mainland Europe. But Morgan sells cones to police forces and
traffic authorities as far away as Saudi Arabia and China, as well as large
and engineering companies across the UK. 'We get orders from all over the
world,' says Morgan. 'One of ours was pulled out of the sea by a man in Fiji
and he requested 5,000.'
Morgan's company makes everything from the diminutive 13-inch traffic cone
to the giant Highwayman. Personalised wedding cones decorated with lace and
frills are available to order and Morgan sells about 50 special black
funeral cones a week. He has even diversified into road signs, barrier
systems, flashing lamps and paint for marking out white and yellow lines.
But the production of around 1.5m cones a year is still the chief
pre-occupation of the 65 staff at the Broughton Poggs plant.
In Britain, the 365-page Traffic Sign Regulation and General Directions
booklet gives precise dimensions and colours of cones, and the layout needed
for certain types of traffic control.
Cones are forever getting stolen, mangled or discoloured, so there is always
fresh demand.
Is Morgan proud of his job?
'Well it's not something I admit to socially, but it's quite satisfying
knowing my product sees people through road works safely.'
What if there is a decline in road building?
'That's fine - old worn out roads are better for us. But if and when work
starts on extending the M25 to 14 lanes, we're going to have a big party.'
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Peter Cook Safety Products.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3089 Plastics Products, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page XIV
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-23</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-FAAACAEIFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941231
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  31 DEC 94 / Food and Drink: Spirit of the Caribbean - Giles MacDonogh
compares the islands' rums
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By GILES MACDONOGH
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Rums reflect the nations that make them,' said Vincent Osborne, the jolly
proprietor of the soon-to-be-three branches of the Brixtonian bars and
restaurants.
'You wouldn't expect much subtlety from a Jamaican. Jamaicans are not subtle
people.' Reading my thoughts, he added that he was not from Jamaica, but
from quite another Caribbean island.
Osborne proved his point in the course of a tasting of a couple of dozen
rums in his Covent Garden branch, Brixtonian Backayard.
Rum is distilled wherever sugar cane is grown and in a few places where it
is not. There is African rum from Nigeria, Kenya or South Africa; Indian rum
reeking of petrol; Australian rum, which in its heyday was aged in old wine
casks from the Hunter Valley; and north and south American rum. The best, of
course, comes from the Caribbean.
Some rums from the former Spanish colonies were predictably fashioned for
the sweet-toothed: Ron Colonial, a golden rum from Guatamala, or Ron Artemi
from the Canary Islands, for example.
Cuba had its own style of white, un-aged rum, of which Bacardi is now the
best known example, even if it is now no longer made in Cuba and is these
days less of a rum than a popular white spirit. If you want to try a Cuban
white rum you would be better off with Havana Club. Both a white rum, and a
three-year-old, golden, banana-smelling rum are available here.
The old French colonies and the two French islands of Martinique and
Guadeloupe (which are now departments of France) make the best rums. Most
are made in column stills which produce a less pungent spirit than that made
in Jamaica, and one which needs a longer process of maturation.
Osborne let me taste a 15-year-old from the famous old Barbancourt estate on
Haiti which was wonderfully complex, if slightly too woody in the mouth. He
charges Pounds 13 a shot for this, but concedes that its rarity together
with the difficulty obtaining it (he has to trawl the bas fonds of Miami to
lay his hands on the odd bottle) tends to push the price up.
Martinique white rums don't impress me much, perhaps because I am reluctant
to see any drink submerged beneath a liquidised fruit cocktail. The Saint
James brand, widely distributed in France, makes a Royal Ambre which despite
a slightly sicky nose has lots of spice on the palate.
Even better were two rums from J. Bailly at Larjus du Carbet in Martinique.
The 1966 was a dream, an absolute must for anyone who doubts rum's ability
to hold its own among the world's great digestifs. From the Domaine de
Montebello came a 1948 rum which was magnificently spicy: cinnamon, cloves
and ginger.
In the old British colonies many of the rums were made in pot stills using
molasses as opposed to the cane juice preferred by the French. The result
can be very 'estery'.
Ben Cross de Chavannes, a veteran rum trader, showed me some startling
figures relating to the ester-count in Jamaican rums. In layman's terms this
means that many Jamaican rums are a good deal more aromatic than malt
whisky. Some of these rums are blended with less pungent distillates before
they are bottled in order to tame their natural explosivity.
Many Jamaican rums are bottled at high strength. These used to be the 'high
wines' - the 'fore-shots' of the distillation which are generally
redistilled because they have an off-flavour or 'feint' . During the Great
War these were the only spirits made available to the Jamaicans, and they
developed a taste for them. Fortunately, perhaps, these are not widely
available.
Anyone wishing to try a subtle white rum from a British island, should
sample The Baron's CSR from St Kitts, which is remarkably smooth. Cockspur
is a golden rum with a well-mannered drink with a faintly nutmeg-like aroma.
Not so Lang's Finest Old Banana. This shoots fruit at you from 30 paces; not
even drowning it in fruit juice was able to suppress its violent bouquet.
Two rather more house-tamed rums are El Dorado Demerara rum (from Guyana)
and Alfred Lamb reserve. The 15-year-old Guyanese rum has a smell which
reminded me of angelica. The Lamb is a rather buttery drink, big and
warming. These two come closest to being after-dinner drinks, but the French
in Martinique and Guadeloupe, I'm sorry to say, do it a lot better.
The Brixtonian. 11 Dorrell Place, London SW9 (071-978 8870); Brixtonian
Backayard, 4 Neal's Yard, London, WC2. (071-240 2769); from early January, a
new Brixtonian will be open at 269 Portobello Road, London W10 (081-968
6188).
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P2085 Distilled and Blended Liquors.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>TECH  Products &amp; Product use.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page XII
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-56</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-FAAACADLFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941231
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  31 DEC 94 / Weekend Money: Top annuity rates
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
An annuity provides guaranteed income for life in return for a lump sum
investment. PURCHASE LIFE ANNUITIES are bought by people wanting extra
regular income. Rates are attractive for older people. The annuity
income is not fully taxable. The table shows rates net of 25 per cent
income tax. Certain rates include 'capital protection' - allowing
the capital invested - less instalments paid to you - to be returned to
your estate when you die.
 ---------------------------------------------------------
Without capital protection      Without capital protection
Male age 70        Annuity      Female age 70      Annuity
                  (Pounds)                        (Pounds)
RNPFN            12,459.60      RNPFN               10,620
Standard Life    12,198.36      Standard Life    10,488.84
Canada Life      11,862.60      Canada Life      10,416.96
 ---------------------------------------------------------
With capital protection            With capital protection
Male age 70        Annuity      Female age 70      Annuity
                  (Pounds)                        (Pounds)
RNPFN            11,139.36      RNPFN             9,895.08
Standard Life    10,931.76      Standard Life     9,803.04
Equitable Life      10,653      Canada Life       9,588.84
 ---------------------------------------------------------
Without capital protection      Without capital protection
Male age 75        Annuity      Female age 75      Annuity
                  (Pounds)                        (Pounds)
RNPFN            14,901.84      RNPFN            12,573.96
Standard Life    14,640.12      Standard Life    12,419.16
Canada Life      14,100.12      Canada Life      12,338.28
 ---------------------------------------------------------
JOINT LIFE - 100% SPOUSE'S BENEFIT
Without capital protection      Without capital protection
Male age 68                     Male age 70
Female age 65      Annuity      Female age 68      Annuity
                  (Pounds)                        (Pounds)
Standard Life     8,457.60      RNPFN             8,959.92
RNPFN             8,446.20      Standard Life     8,955.36
Canada Life       8,327.16      Canada Life       8,816.04
 ---------------------------------------------------------
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
Payments are monthly in arrears, without a guarantee period. Rates are
at 28th December 1994. Figures assume an annuity purchase price of
Pounds 100,000 and are shown net of tax. A tax rate of 25 per cent has
been applied. RNPFN annuities are available only to nurses and allied
workers.
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
Source: Annuity Bureau: 071-620 4090.
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6311 Life Insurance.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>STATS  Statistics.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page V
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-143</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-FAAACAA6FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941231
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  31 DEC 94 / Watering hole
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
The River Ouse floods buildings in York after heavy rain and gales yesterday
which also hit Wales and the West Country
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9229 Public Order and Safety, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 5
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3005</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELOCSADWFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941215
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  15 DEC 94 / People: Non-executive directors
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Brian Hardy, director of finance at Burmah Castrol, at STOREHOUSE; he will
become chairman of the board's audit committee on the retirement of Margaret
Downes next year.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Storehouse.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P5651 Family Clothing Stores.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 22
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3008</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELOCSADTFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941215
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  15 DEC 94 / People: Bodies politic
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Paul Barry, md EC Harris International, has been elected chairman of the
BRITISH CONSULTANTS BUREAU.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P8611 Business Associations.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 22
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3015</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELOCSADMFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941215
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  15 DEC 94 / Technology: Whispers from the runway - A transport system
that will be propelled by magnetic attraction
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By MICHAEL LINDEMANN
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
For the past 10 years a 90-tonne machine has been tearing around an elevated
concrete track in north-west Germany, reaching speeds of up to 450kph but
making none of the noise made by aircraft travelling at that speed. It is
the Transrapid high-speed train, also known as the whispering arrow.
Now, after years of debate, the German government has approved plans to
build a 284km track between Berlin and Hamburg, Germany's two biggest
cities, in a move that is expected to take passengers away from those
airlines flying the route.
The Transrapid will be the world's first long-distance transport system
propelled by magnetic levitation, a technology that Thyssen, the German
conglomerate, has been developing. Instead of conventional engines, the
Transrapid is propelled by magnetic fields. It has no wheels and rather than
run on conventional railway tracks it clutches a concrete runway rather like
the runner on a curtain rail.
The technology dates from the 1920s when Hermann Kemper, an electronic
engineer who ran a meat packing business near the present 32km test site in
Emsland, began poring over papers about the theory of magnetic levitation.
Kemper developed a model in his cellar where objects were fired along
runways by passing mains electricity through electromagnets mounted on the
objects and on the runway.
In 1934 he registered his patents and tried unsuccessfully to persuade
Siemens, the electronics company, to take up his ideas.
What was missing, according to Hans Georg Raschbichler, an engineer from
Thyssen Henschel, the locomotive builder, was the means to produce and
transport large amounts of electricity at split-second intervals. 'They
didn't have the sort of high-tech electronics which exist today,' he says in
his office in Munich.
Now that large amounts of electricity can be passed around a grid and
engineers can regulate the 10mm gap between the runway and the vehicle, two
key bits of technology are available which mean that Kemper's model can
become a real ity.
The Transrapid operates on different principles from the maglev technology
used elsewhere in the world. Conventional magnetic levitation works by using
the repellant force of superconductive magnets of opposite polarities. In
the Transrapid, propulsion comes from the force of magnetic attraction.
By passing electrical current through a stator pack, the stationary part of
an electric motor which is laid out on the underside of a concrete runway, a
wandering magnetic field is created. This magnetic field - called wandering
because it moves down the runway - is attracted or excited by levitation
magnets mounted on the underside of the Transrapid, so propelling the
vehicle forward.
The Transrapid picks up speed proportional to the increase in electrical
current; the opposite happens when the frequency is reduced. If there is a
power failure, batteries on board the Transrapid are used to power the eddy
current braking system and to guide the vehicle to an emergency stop on the
runway.
The vehicle glides about 10mm above the concrete runway, a gap which is
measured by a computerised sensor: if it becomes smaller, the computer
orders more electricity, less if it becomes bigger. The process is repeated
thousands of times, keeping the gap constant and enabling the magnet to pull
the Transrapid.
Raschbichler heads a team of engineers at Thyssen Henschel which ran the
Transrapid 07, the seventh prototype, up to a maximum speed of 450kph last
year. They are now putting it through 500,000km of tests before it can be
licensed to operate.
Tests have shown that the vehicle uses less energy and is quieter than the
French TGV (Train a Grande Vitesse) or the German InterCity Express (ICE),
the two high-speed trains which are its main competitors. Stand 25m away
from a Transrapid passing at 300kph, and the maximum noise level recorded is
87 decibels - less than a freight train travelling at 100kmh. Tests by
independent engineers recorded about 100 decibels for a TGV travelling at
the same speed.
Because the Transrapid glides above a concrete runway it does not need to
overcome the resistance between track and wheels which traditional railway
technology still has to grapple with. That means, according to Thyssen
Henschel, that the Transrapid uses around 30 per cent less energy than a
high-speed train travelling at the same speed.
The government hopes that by 2004 a runway - similar to the present test
track - will be built and that more than 14m passengers a year will be
hurtling between Germany's two biggest cities. A journey that now takes more
than three hours by train will take just 55 minutes by Transrapid.
The DM5.6bn (Pounds 2.3bn) needed to finance the runway and infrastructure
will be put up by the federal government, and Thyssen has created a company
together with Lufthansa, the national airline, and Deutsche Bahn, the state
railway, which have to find DM4.8bn to operate the service.
The Japanese are working on similar technology but opted in the early 1970s
for an electrodynamic levitation system - where magnets repel rather than
attract each other. The different system also creates a 10cm gap, rather
than 10mm, between the vehicle and the runway which the Japanese say is
better suited to deal with earthquake risks.
The Transrapid technology creates magnetic fields of about 40 amps - no
bigger than those created by an electric razor - while the Japanese have to
grapple with big magnetic fields of up to 700,000 amps. About four times as
much electricity is needed to control the movement of the Japanese train
across such big magnetic fields and Thyssen says they are so powerful it is
thought people wearing pacemakers will not be able to use the trains.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>DEZ  Germany, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3743 Railroad Equipment.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>TECH  Products &amp; Product use.
    CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 22
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3048</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELOCSACPFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941215
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  15 DEC 94 / Increased use of Thames urged
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
More use should be made of the River Thames for tourists, commuters and
commercial users, the River Thames Working Group, chaired by transport
minister Mr Steven Norris, said yesterday.
It called for better promotion and co-ordination of tourist passenger
services and other leisure amenities on the river.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P4489 Water Passenger Transportation, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>RES  Facilities.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 8
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3061</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELOCSACCFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941215
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  15 DEC 94 / Increased use of Thames urged
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
More use should be made of the River Thames for tourists, commuters and
commercial users, the River Thames Working Group, chaired by transport
minister Mr Steven Norris, said yesterday.
It called for better promotion and co-ordination of tourist passenger
services and other leisure amenities on the river, a review of the location
of piers and further promotion of opportunities to develop bulk cargoes on
the river through the freight facilities grant scheme.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P4489 Water Passenger Transportation, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>RES  Facilities.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 8
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3089</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELOCSABKFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941215
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  15 DEC 94 / World Trade News: Aker wins Phillips contract
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By KAREN FOSSLI
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   OSLO
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Aker Verdal, a yard owned by the Aker group of Norway, yesterday was awarded
a NKr240m (Dollars 35.3m) contract by Phillips Petroleum Norway to build a
steel substructure for the 2/4X oil platform to be installed as part of the
Norwegian North Sea Ekofisk upgrading project.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Aker Verdal.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>NOZ  Norway, West Europe.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3533 Oil and Gas Field Machinery.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>MKTS  Contracts.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 5
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3139</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELOCSAIZFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941214
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  14 DEC 94 / World News in Brief: Saatchi &amp; Saatchi
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Non-executive directors who favour a name change at the advertising group
have been warned that founder and executive chairman Maurice Saatchi may
quit if his surname is dropped.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Saatchi and Saatchi.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P7311 Advertising Agencies.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  People.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
International Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3192</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELNEAAFSFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941214
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  14 DEC 94 / International Company News: Taiwanese groups face setback
over eurobond issuance
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By LAURA TYSON
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   TAIPEI
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Hopes that Taiwanese companies could raise fresh equity through the launch
of convertible eurobonds look set to be dashed as the first of a rush of
issues since 1989 comes up for repayment later this month.
The authorities in Taipei have yet to reach agreement on rules allowing
foreigners to convert their holdings into listed shares, although the matter
has been the subject of debate since Yuen Foong Yu Paper (YFY), a listed
paper manufacturer, issued Taiwan's first convertible bond in 1989.
YFY may thus have to redeem its Dollars 120m issue in cash when a put option
falls due on December 21.
To date, 29 Taiwanese companies have issued euroconvertible bonds, mostly in
the past year. But because foreign individuals are not permitted to buy
Taiwan shares directly, government departments have been unable to solve the
dilemma presented by conversion.
The central bank and the finance ministry, to which the Securities and
Exchange Commission reports, have agreed in principle that convertible bonds
may be switched into global depository receipts. However, the details of
such a conversion method have yet to be worked out.
Investor appetite for Taiwanese paper has largely evaporated due to
oversupply following a flurry of issues this year. Secondary trading has
dried up and proposed new issues are being met coolly amid rising interest
rates and concern over the lack of convertibility.
In YFY's case, the point is moot as the current share price makes conversion
unattractive. But several other issues have met criteria for conversion set
out in issue documents.
A number of Taiwanese companies have delayed or cancelled planned
convertible issues as the cost has risen almost to the level of raising
funds domestically. In October Formosa Plastics Corp, the petrochemical
company, shelved plans to raise USDollars 300m in convertible bonds.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>TWZ  Taiwan, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9311 Finance, Taxation, and Monetary Policy.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 25
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3210</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELNEAAFAFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941214
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  14 DEC 94 / UK Company News: Seton buys Orovite
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Seton Healthcare Group is acquiring SmithKline Beecham's Orovite, the
multi-vitamin supplement. It is paying Pounds 3.78m cash for the trade mark
and goodwill. In 1993, the brand made a gross profit of Pounds 810,000 on
sales of Pounds 1.23m.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Seton Healthcare Group.
    SmithKline Beecham.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
    USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6794 Patent Owners and Lessors.
    P3841 Surgical and Medical Instruments.
    P3842 Surgical Appliances and Supplies.
    P2834 Pharmaceutical Preparations.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>TECH  Patents &amp; Licences.
    COMP  Disposals.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 22
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3302</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELNEAACQFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941214
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  14 DEC 94 / People: Non-executive directors
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Geoffrey Whalen, soon to retire as deputy chairman of Peugeot Talbot in the
UK, at T&amp;N.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>T and N.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3089 Plastics Products, NEC.
    P3292 Asbestos Products.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 13
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3303</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELNEAACPFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941214
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  14 DEC 94 / People: Non-executive directors
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Lawrence Urquhart, a non-executive director since 1991, as chairman at
ENGLISH CHINA CLAYS when Lord Chilver retires after the agm next April.
Urquhart is chairman of Burmah Castrol and deputy chairman of Scottish
Widows.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>English China Clays.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P1459 Clay and Related Minerals, NEC.
    P1455 Kaolin and Ball Clay.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 13
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3384</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELNEAAAGFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941214
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  14 DEC 94 / World News in Brief: French swoop
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Police arrested 42 people across France on suspicion of belonging to the
Order of the Solar Temple doomsday cult which claimed 53 lives in
Switzerland and Canada in October.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>FRZ  France, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9221 Police Protection.
    P8661 Religious Organizations.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3392</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELNEAAGRFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941213
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  13 DEC 94 / World News in Brief: Swiss accept brothel
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Switzerland's first official brothel will open in a converted office
building in Zurich after the city authorities granted a building permit to
an entrepreneur.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>CHZ  Switzerland, West Europe.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P7299 Miscellaneous Personal Services, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
International Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3435</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELNDJAFMFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941213
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  13 DEC 94 / UK Company News: Guinness Peat buy
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Guinness Peat, the UK investment vehicle of New Zealand entrepreneur Sir Ron
Brierley, has acquired 7.5m ordinary shares, representing 26.8 per cent of
the issued share capital, of Turners &amp; Growers.
The NZDollars 8.4m (Pounds 3.4m) deal gives Guinness Peat a total of 28.8
per cent in the New Zealand company, which deals in the marketing of fruit
and produce and vehicle auctioneering.
Turners &amp; Growers reported a net loss of NZDollars 1.57m for the year to
March 31, prior to an abnormal loss of NZDollars 3.88m. Assets stood at
NZDollars 49.2m.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Guinness Peat Group.
    Turners and Growers.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
    NZZ  New Zealand.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P5148 Fresh Fruits and Vegetables.
    P7389 Business Services, NEC.
    P6719 Holding Companies, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Shareholding.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 26
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3496</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELNDJADXFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941213
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  13 DEC 94 / Letters to the Editor: VAT on fuel - democracy and penalties
(1)
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   From Mr JOSEPH WRIGHT
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Sir, Is democracy really the winner, as is stated by William Bakewell
(Letters, December 9) in response to the government's defeat over an
increase in VAT on domestic fuel?
Perhaps it is when one considers that the majority of the electorate would
not seem to support the move.
However, as far as parliamentary democracy is concerned can we be so sure?
Did every member of all the opposition parties vote according to their
conscience, or did they vote politically to bring about a humiliating defeat
on the government?
Equally, did all the unrebellious Conservatives vote with the government for
the former reason or were they simply trying to prevent such a humiliation?
If political motives did indeed determine how MPs voted, then democracy has
not been served.
The outcome in reality acts merely as an example of how enormous political
power can be wielded by small minority groups or parties whatever electoral
system is prevalent when governments rule through coalition or small
minorities.
Joseph Winner,
Philips Communication
and Security Systems,
Cromwell Road,
Cambridge
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9311 Finance, Taxation, and Monetary Policy.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>GOVT  Taxes.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 17
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3505</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELNDJADOFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941213
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  13 DEC 94 / People: Non-executive directors
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Raymond Seitz, former US ambassador to the Court of St James, at GEC.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>General Electric Co.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3612 Transformers, Ex Electronic.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 15
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3513</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELNDJADGFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941213
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  13 DEC 94 / People: Williams Holdings
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Chris Davies, who has been with WILLIAMS HOLDINGS since 1982, has been
appointed operations director.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Williams Holdings.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3429 Hardware, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 15
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3521</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELNDJAC8FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941213
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  13 DEC 94 / Technology: The weapons of a killer - The search for what
causes cancer has thrown up hundreds of suspects, from smoking to driving
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By CLIVE COOKSON
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Advice for avoiding cancer: Don't smoke. Hide from the sun. Eat fruit and
vegetables. Join the upper classes. Employ a chauffeur and don't look out of
the car window.
Epidemiologists estimate 75-80 per cent of all cancers are preventable, in
the sense that they are triggered by features of the individual's lifestyle
and environment. The problem is identifying the avoidable risks. A few are
well known and easy to act on; much the most obvious example is smoking.
Most risks, however, are less well defined and harder to avoid. For
instance, cancer as a whole is more common - and more likely to be fatal -
among the 'lower' social classes. This is true even when the statistics are
adjusted to take account of all known risk factors such as smoking, diet and
access to health care.
Researchers are coming to the conclusion that there is something
intrinsically unhealthy about being near the bottom of the social pecking
order, even if you follow the rules for healthy living. Sally Macintyre,
director of the Medical Research Council's Medical Sociology Unit in
Glasgow, says the mechanism of this effect is far from clear, though it
appears that 'repeated psycho-social stress' somehow depresses the immune
system.
Hundreds of different risk factors have been suggested for cancer - some of
them an inextricable part of modern life. For example, Australian research
has shown a statistical correlation between driving and cancer. The theory
is that the brain responds to moving surroundings by priming the body
chemically for movement that never takes place; the resulting chemical
imbalance may trigger cancers. More concern has been expressed about
man-made hormones, particularly in the contraceptive pill. Clinical studies
involving tens of thousands of women have shown no general increase in
cancer among long-term pill users, though some groups may be at slightly
greater risk of developing breast or cervical cancer.
But epidemiologists say people should not be too concerned about minor or
speculative causes of cancer, when smoking and poor diet are so much more
important.
'One of the biggest myths in recent years is that there is a cancer epidemic
caused by exposure to radiation, pollution, pesticides and food additives,'
says Sir Richard Doll of the Imperial Cancer Research Fund's cancer studies
unit in Oxford. 'These factors have very little to do with the majority of
cancers.'
Epidemiologists are confident tobacco is implicated in about 30 per cent of
cancer deaths in Europe and North America. They are far less sure about food
and drink; a typical estimate is that diet is involved in 35 per cent of
cancer deaths.
Because there can be a delay of several decades between starting to smoke
and the onset of disease, the big rise in lung cancer did not begin until
the 1940s among men and the 1970s among women (see chart). The male lung
cancer rate is falling in countries such as the US and UK where large
numbers of men gave up smoking in the 1960s and 1970s, but it is rising
throughout the developing world. Female lung cancer rates are increasing
everywhere.
Although lung cancer is the most obvious effect of smoking, 12 other cancers
are linked to the habit, as well as cardiovascular and other diseases.
However, if an individual smoker gives up before becoming ill, he or she can
avoid most of the risk of dying from tobacco. Ten years after stopping, half
of the smoker's additional cancer risk will have disappeared.
In contrast to smoking and lung cancer, there is no cancer epidemic clearly
linked to changing diet. On the contrary, the most striking trend is the
long-term decline in stomach cancer in Europe and North America - a fall
widely attributed to modern methods of food preservation and storage which
prevent the formation of carcinogenic decay products.
Although colo-rectal cancer rates have remained steady for several decades
in the west, those in Japan have risen rapidly to European levels - probably
because the Japanese diet has become westernised with more meat and fat
eaten.
Epidemiologists say there is overwhelming evidence that a diet rich in fruit
and vegetables reduces the risk of cancer. But they do not know how the
protective effect works.
A favourite scientific theory is that anti-oxidant nutrients, such as
vitamins E and C and beta-carotene, play a protective role by scavenging
'free radicals' which can damage a cell's genetic material. Food supplements
containing these nutrients have become very popular. as a result, although
there is not yet conclusive clinical evidence to prove their effectiveness.
The next stage, according to speakers at the UK Biochemical Society
Conference this week, will be genetic engineering of crops to make more of
these protective nutrients. Catherine Rice-Evans, a biochemistry professor
at Guy's Hospital, London, predicts: 'The introduction of plants that have
been manipulated to produce more effective anti-oxidants should be possible
within five years.'
IN THIS SERIES:
NOVEMBER 29
Introduction. The growing toll of cancer worldwide. Why the disease is
responding better to treatment in the young. The worldwide market for cancer
drugs. Who is spending what on research.
JANUARY
Diagnosis and screening. Genetic susceptibility. Scans. Identifying cancer
markers in the blood. Politics and economics of screening.
FEBRUARY
Chemotherapy. Drugs to kill rapidly dividing cancer cells. Reducing
multi-drug resistance. Anti-nausea drugs and other ways of reducing side
effects. Hormone-based treatments. Photodynamic therapy. Herbal and
alterative remedies.
MARCH
Radiotherapy. X-rays. Gamma rays. Neutron beams. Heavy ions. Magic bullets.
Antibodies and fusion toxins aimed at cancer cells.
APRIL
Genetic treatment and other biotech approaches. Gene therapy and anti-sense.
Cell migration and adhesion. Apoptosis and cell suicide. Immunostimulants.
Cell growth factors. Interferons and interleukins.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P8731 Commercial Physical Research.
    P9431 Administration of Public Health Programs.
    P2711 Newspapers.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
    TECH  Products &amp; Product use.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 13
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3523</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELNDJAC6FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941213
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  13 DEC 94 / Technology: Drugs to tackle infections
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By DANIEL GREEN
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Some microscopic bacteria and viruses are carcinogenic. Infections may
account for 10-15 per cent of all cancers, according to epidemiologists at
the Imperial Cancer Research Fund.
Five kinds of germ have been identified as possible cancer triggers:
Helicobacter pylori is a bacterium which survives in the stomach. It
irritates the stomach lining which may respond with ulcers or cancer.
Epstein-Barr virus is associated with Burkitt's lymphoma and nasopharyngeal
carcinoma, cancers more common in central Africa and China respectively than
in the west. EBV may be linked to cancer in people with suppressed immune
systems, perhaps after an organ transplant.
Human Papilloma virus (HPV) causes genital warts. Some sub-types have been
linked to cervical and vaginal cancers.
Hepatitis B virus (HBV) survives for long periods in about 10 per cent of
the population, who are then at increased risk from liver disease, including
cancer.
Human T-cell Lymphotropic viruses (HTLV) have been implicated in leukaemia
in some populations such as Japan.
In principle, antibiotics and vaccines can beat these infections.
There are several hepatitis B vaccines on the market. Biotechnology
companies, including Isis in the US and Cantab in the UK, and the UK's
Cancer Research Campaign, are developing better HBV vaccines. The CRC says
its vaccine might even help patients already with cancer. Work is being done
too on broad spectrum antiviral drugs. California's Gilead has a material
which shows promise against EBV and HPV. And an industry is growing up
around H pylori. Diagnostics companies are launching saliva tests to replace
blood or tissue analysis, and Swedish drug company Astra this year won UK
approval for an antibiotic-based ulcer treatment.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P8731 Commercial Physical Research.
    P2836 Biological Products Ex Diagnostic.
    P9431 Administration of Public Health Programs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 13
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3551</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELNDJACEFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941213
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  13 DEC 94 / Wash and brush up
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
A worker sweeps up yesterday under the Queen Elizabeth 2 at Blohm &amp; Voss's
shipyard in Hamburg, where the cruise liner is undergoing its biggest refit
for 25 years
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Blohm und Voss.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3731 Ship Building and Repairing.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Company News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 9
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3590</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELNDJABBFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941213
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  13 DEC 94 / Shanghai share fraud arrest
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By REUTER
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   SHANGHAI
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Police have arrested a top company official in the biggest corruption case
in the history of the Shanghai Stock Exchange. Mr Zhu Jianping, 48, deputy
general manager of Shanghai Rubber Belt, allegedly earned Yn800,000 (Pounds
60,000) by selling shares in his own company. The announcement of his arrest
adds to the woes of a market tarnished by speculation and battered by a wave
of selling in the past several months. 'He's nothing more than a worm in the
reform process,' one prosecutor said.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Shanghai Rubber Belt.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>CNZ  China, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6231 Security and Commodity Exchanges.
    P9651 Regulation of Miscellaneous Commercial Sectors.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  People.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 6
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3625</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELNDJAACFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941213
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  13 DEC 94 / World News in Brief: Warning on China
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
China is more of a risk than businesses are prepared to admit and it is far
from certain that there will be an easy change of power when Deng Xiaoping
dies, according to an Economist Intelligence Unit report.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>CNZ  China, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9611 Administration of General Economic Programs.
    P9311 Finance, Taxation, and Monetary Policy.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3634</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELOCSAIPFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941212
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  12 DEC 94 / World News in Brief: Search for sailors
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Poor weather conditions disrupted the search for 22 crewmen still missing
since the Ukrainian-flagged cargo ship Salvador Allende sank in the North
Atlantic on Friday.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>CAZ  Canada.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9229 Public Order and Safety, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
International Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3654</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELMDEAEWFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941212
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  12 DEC 94 / Emerging Markets: Tibet
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
The world's highest stock exchange in Lhasa, capital of China's Tibet
region, has seen its highest daily turnover of Yn5m (Dollars 588,000) since
it opened in January.
The stock exchange has more than 2,000 members in a city of just 180,000.
The exchange is a member of China's two stock exchanges in Shanghai and
Shenzhen and trading is linked.
Edited by John Pitt. Further coverage of emerging markets appears daily on
the World Stock Markets page.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>CNZ  China, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6231 Security and Commodity Exchanges.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>MKTS  Market data.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 23
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3656</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELMDEAEUFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941212
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  12 DEC 94 / Emerging Markets: Nigeria
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Nigeria has said that it will make funds available next year for the
formation and operation of a commodity exchange and futures market.
General Oladipo Diya, the chief of general staff, said that the planned
commodity market, 'is one of the measures being taken by this administration
to redeem the country's ailing economy'.
The government was studying the workings of commodity exchanges in Tokyo,
London and Kuala Lumpur.
Edited by John Pitt. Further coverage of emerging markets appears daily on
the World Stock Markets page.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>NGZ  Nigeria, Africa.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6231 Security and Commodity Exchanges.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>MKTS  Market data.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 23
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3675</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELMDEAEBFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941212
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  12 DEC 94 / UK Company News: Grand Central Inv
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Grand Central Investment Holdings, the food group with interests in Asia
Pacific, is selling 4,000 acres of cocoa and coconut plantations in Malaysia
as part of its plans to sell its non-core commodity based businesses.
It is receiving about Pounds 7m from Bukit resulting in a net gain of Pounds
300,000. The deal will also cut Grand Central debts by about Pounds 5m.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Grand Central Investment Holdings.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>MYZ  Malaysia, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P0179 Fruits and Tree Nuts, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Disposals.
    RES  Facilities.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 20
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3740</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELMDEACIFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941212
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  12 DEC 94 / This Week: Music
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By PETER ASPDEN
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
It is time to start thinking about that crucial soundtrack to the Christmas
dinner; and thanks to the extraordinary commercial success of religious
music over the last 12 months, record companies have provided us with a
bewildering choice.
For those who helped put Gregorian chants at the top of the classical charts
for much of the year, Eternal Peace: Gregorian Chant for Christmas (Deutsche
Grammophon) provides a timely seasonal top-up of spiritual sustenance. The
choir of the monks of Montserrat Abbey sing the 12 Responsories of Matins at
Christmas, while the First Mass for Christmas is performed by the
Benedictine Abbey at Munsterschwarzach.
Christmas with the Academy (Decca) is more of a mixed bag: Sir Neville
Marriner conducts the Academy of St Martin in the Fields in a performance of
popular classics such as 'Ding Dong] Merrily on High' and 'Hark the Herald
Angels Sing'. More adventurous is Carols from the Old and New Worlds
(Harmonia Mundi), in which Paul Hillier and the Theatre of Voices superbly
rattle through a host of unfamiliar arrangements of much-loved tunes.
On the splendidly-priced Naxos label, Jeremy Summerly directs the Oxford
Camerata in Medieval Carols, a collection which includes 'Ave Maria',
'Gaudete Christus est Natus' and Hildegard of Bingen's haunting monophonic
'O Viridissima Virga'. The historical archive label Nimbus joins in the fun
with The Spirit of Christmas Past; highlights include Caruso singing
'Cantique de Noel' and the awesome Ernestine Schumann-Heink's 'Stille
Nacht'.
For those who find it inconceivable to think of a Christmas without the
likes of Slade (above) and Gary Glitter, The Best Christmas ..Ever (Virgin)
runs through 42 pop classics (including the pleasant surprise of Miles
Davis's 'Blue Christmas'). Older generations in search of easy listening for
a difficult day will prefer, on the same label, Yule Cool featuring Perry
Como, Dean Martin and Nat King Cole.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3652 Prerecorded Records and Tapes.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>TECH  Products &amp; Product use.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 11
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3756</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELMDEAB2FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941212
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  12 DEC 94 / Concern on ethnic employment
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
People from ethnic minorities are much more likely to be unemployed than
their white counterparts, although far higher numbers of young ethnic
minority Britons are studying full-time, says a report today by the Equal
Opportunities Commission and the Commission for Racial Equality.
The unemployment rate for ethnic minority women is 16 per cent, compared
with 6 per cent for white women. Ethnic minority men have a 20 per cent
unemployment rate compared with 11 per cent for white men.
The report found that even when members of ethnic minority groups attained
higher qualifications - above A-level or equivalent - unemployment levels
remain far higher than among white men and women.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9441 Administration of Social and Manpower Programs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>ECON  Employment &amp; unemployment.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 8
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3776</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELMDEABIFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941212
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  12 DEC 94 / Peace prize talks make no headway
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By REUTER
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   OSLO
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Israeli and PLO leaders yesterday parted in disagreement over the peace
process, after receiving the 1994 Nobel Peace Prize for their accord on
Palestinian self-rule, Reuter reports from Oslo.
Israeli Prime Minister Yitzhak Rabin, Foreign Minister Shimon Peres and
Palestine Liberation Organisation leader Yassir Arafat made no breakthrough
in talks on the terms for much-delayed Palestinian elections - the next
stage in the peace process.
The two sides agreed to intensify high- and middle- level talks on the
critical second stage of the deal - redeployment of Israeli troops away from
Palestinian population centres on the West Bank before Palestinian elections
are held.
Mr Rabin said Israeli security concerns must be dealt with in a balanced
way, warning: 'Short cuts might lead to catastrophe.' Mr Arafat, in his
acceptance speech on Saturday, insisted on the withdrawal of Israeli troops
from Arab towns on the West Bank before elections can be held.
Israeli and PLO officials said their delegations would meet again in Cairo
on Wednesday for further talks.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>ILZ  Israel, Middle East.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9721 International Affairs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 6
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3783</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELMDEABBFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941212
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  12 DEC 94 / Tokyo and Seoul drop rivalry in spirit of business
partnership: Michiyo Nakamoto and John Burton on a turning point in
relations
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By MICHIYO NAKAMOTO and JOHN BURTON
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
The decision by Japan's Mitsubishi Motors to buy steel sheet from Korea's
Pohang Iron and Steel on a long-term basis marks a turning point in the
countries' post-war industrial relations.
From the Japanese perspective, last week's contract signals a growing
willingness to set aside national prejudices and to recognise its
neighbour's industrial competitiveness. For the Korean steel industry, it
offers a sweet victory over its most formidable rivals and a strong vote of
confidence from the Japanese motor industry.
Japanese and Korean business relations have long been clouded by intense
rivalry, mutual suspicion and a bitter antagonism that can be traced back
centuries. But changes in the quality of Korean products and the yen's
appreciation, forcing Japanese companies to diversify their sources, have
prompted rivals to become partners.
The older generation of businessmen on both sides of the Sea of Japan often
find it difficult to overcome their deeply ingrained prejudices about the
other. 'Generally, Japanese tend to look down on Koreans,' concedes one
Japanese businessman who works for a major manufacturer. 'Our chairman used
to say there are countries that are likeable and those that are not,' he
says.
'It's a very complex and tangled relationship,' observes a foreign
businessman who works in a leading Japanese electronics company. 'The
general feeling among Japanese businessmen is that you can't work with the
Koreans.'
The Japanese are aware of the bitterness Koreans still feel about the
sufferings inflicted by Japanese soldiers during the second world war.
Korean hostility towards Japanese businesses in the 1960s and 1970s has also
left a scar on Japan's corporate memory.
Cultural differences also play a part. Japanese social etiquette does not
sit easily with the straightforward approach of many Koreans, which many
Japanese consider unduly aggressive .
But the Japanese are also aware that the Koreans are similar in their work
ethic, in their ability to work effectively in groups and their loyalty. The
combination of such strong differences and similarities, and a deep
familiarity with each other's strengths and weaknesses, has added to the
complex feelings between the neighbours.
'The Koreans know the Japanese very, very well and know what irks them, and
that is one of the reasons the Japanese tend to be wary of doing business
with them,' said one foreign businessman in Tokyo.
That fear is supported by the Japanese recognition of the potential threat
Korean industry poses to Japanese industry. Korea has maintained a constant
trade deficit with Japan since diplomatic relations were established in 1965
and the gap is expected to grow to almost Dollars 12bn (Pounds 7.3bn) this
year. This reflects Korea's heavy dependence on Japanese capital goods,
including machinery and components. Korea has tried to reduce the deficit by
improving its domestic subcontracting network, and increasing spending on
product research and development.
Seoul has also lobbied Japan to open its markets to Korean imports and
encourage Japanese component manufacturers to establish production
facilities in Korea. But efforts to attract new investment have met with
little success so far. Japanese companies are afraid that increased
industrial investments will strengthen Korea's competitiveness.
On the other hand, Korean fears about Japanese economic dominance were
reflected in the recent controversy over Samsung's entry into the car
industry with the technical help of Nissan of Japan. Critics of the deal
said Samsung's co-operation with Nissan would increase car imports from
Japan and hinder efforts to promote technological independence in the Korean
car industry, which has been dependent on Japanese technology.
Samsung won government approval for the project only after it promised to
increase the local content of its cars from between 70 and 80 per cent in
1998, when manufacturing begins, to 98 per cent by 2003.
Korea banned imports of most Japanese consumer products in the 1970s. Seoul
has agreed to halve by 1997 the number of Japanese products on the 'import
diversification' list which now excludes 250 items.
Executives from the Korean electronics and car industries acknowledge that
the quality and technology of their products often lag behind that of their
Japanese rivals although the gap is narrowing in some fields. In
semiconductors, Korea has overtaken Japan as the leading maker of current
generation 4-megabit dynamic random access memory chips. Japanese officials
are quick to point out that these chips make up only a small part of the
semiconductor market and that Japanese makers are three to five years ahead
in advanced semiconductor technologies.
Nevertheless, 'there is a feeling that the Koreans are doing very well in
D-Rams and that they are very aggressive and formidable competitors,' says
an official at a leading Japanese semiconductor maker.
The yen's sharp appreciation and the structural changes facing Japanese
industry are providing strong incentives for Japanese companies to overcome
their reluctance to rely on Korea.
Electronics companies, for example, are also beginning to recognise that
teaming up with Korean competitors can help them succeed. NEC has agreed to
share information with Samsung on developments each makes on future
generation D-Rams.
The change in generations is also playing a part, as younger Japanese and
Koreans with few memories of the war and similar western views, rise to
managerial positions.
As one mid-level Japanese businessman at a leading company says: 'If there
is a good partner, Korean or otherwise, we would not miss an opportunity to
do business with them.'
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>JPZ  Japan, Asia.
    KRZ  South Korea, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9611 Administration of General Economic Programs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 5
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3832</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELMDEAGDFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941210
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  10 DEC 94 / Weekend Money (Financial Planning): Top annuity rates
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
An annuity provides a guaranteed income for life in return for a lump
sum investment. The bulk of the fund built up by many types of pension
plan must be used in this way. Annuity income is fully taxable. This
week's table shows the best rates for PERSONAL PENSION ANNUITIES which
are used for personal pension plans and the previous retirement annuity
contracts. The rates in the chart do not include inflation proofing.
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
Male age 55     Annuity            Female age 50    Annuity (-0.01%)*
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
RNPFN           Pounds 7,696.20    Norwich Union     Pounds 6,841.56
Sun Life        Pounds 7,539.24    Sun Life          Pounds 6,827.76
Standard Life   Pounds 7,500.96    RNPFN             Pounds 6,806.40
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
Male age 60     Annuity (%)        Female age 60     Annuity (%)
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
RNPFN           Pounds 8,456.40    RNPFN             Pounds 7,716.84
Standard Life   Pounds 8,182.68    Sun Life          Pounds 7,516.44
Sun Life        Pounds 8,158.32    Norwich Union     Pounds 7,495.56
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
Male age 70     Annuity (%)        Female age 70     Annuity (%)
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
RNPFN           Pounds 11,154.12   RNPFN             Pounds 9,666.24
Sun Life        Pounds 10,429.20   Sun Life          Pounds 9,083.88
Standard Life   Pounds 10,380.24   Norwich Union     Pounds 8,999.28
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
JOINT LIFE - 100% SPOUSE'S BENEFIT
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
Male age 60                        Male age 65
Female age 57   Annuity(-0.01%*)   Female age 63     Annuity (%)
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
RNPFN           Pounds 6,908.64    RNPFN             Pounds 7,467.12
Sun Life        Pounds 6,905.16    Sun Life          Pounds 7,330.08
Norwich Union   Pounds 6,892.56    Norwich Union     Pounds 7,279.56
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
Month's movement
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
Payments are monthly in arrears, without a guarantee period and
without escalation. Rates are as at December 6 1994. Figures
assume an annuity purchase price of Pounds 75,000 after paying
tax free cash of Pounds 25,000 and are shown gross. RNPFN
annuities are available only to nurses and allied workers.
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
Source: Annuity Bureau: 071-620 4090.
 ---------------------------------------------------------------------
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6311 Life Insurance.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>STATS  Statistics.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 9
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3898</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELLBEAEKFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941210
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  10 DEC 94 / Fashion: How the smart set will dress / What special people
wear on a special day
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By AVRIL GROOM
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
The new film The Nightmare Before Christmas, is a children's story but you
could be forgiven for thinking that it describes the panic-stricken weeks of
December in the life of a woman juggling job and family. Work schedules are
telescoped by the impending long break, and the pressure of shopping
escalates.
If you are in charge you must not forget the details crucial to the smooth
running of Christmas day. All this means that you find yourself firmly at
the bottom of the shopping list. This is a pity, for Christmas dressing
deserves a little thought. It is a day of oddly juxtaposed activities where
few rules apply. A leisurely, glamorous breakfast may be interrupted by
hectic present-opening with the children. A trip to church may be followed
by making the gravy.
We all imagine that those who live high-profile lives, who appear to have
made it in life, have sorted out such dilemmas. To find out, we asked a
selection of successful career women and some prominent social high-flyers
to give us their guide to Christmas and how to wear (and bear) it.
BREAKFAST
Rosa Monckton plans to spend Christmas morning at her London flat with her
husband, journalist Dominic Lawson, and daughter Savannah, two. 'We will
have been to midnight Mass but Savannah will be up and excited by 7am so
we'll start then and have a long, leisurely breakfast. Later we may go to my
parents for a traditional lunch.
'I don't want to plan at home because I organise very publicly at work right
up until Christmas Eve. I certainly shan't plan what to wear; clothes are a
low priority. Comfort is essential. I shall assume I have something
suitable, like a wonderful velvet dressing gown, in my wardrobe. Though I
could easily be wrong]'
Patricia Hodge, the actress, currently starring in The Prime of Miss Jean
Brodie at the Strand Theatre in London, will be working until the end of the
Christmas Eve matinee. 'I love 'doing' Christmas, although the preparation
is an enormous headache. I take it in turns with my sister. This is her year
luckily - I have only one day off. There'll be about 20 for lunch and we all
help.
'I shopped in the autumn for Christmas clothes that would be flexible for
other occasions. This silk chenille sweater and panne velvet skirt have the
right mood together but look different when worn with other things. I'll put
a jokey Christmas apron over them for helping in the kitchen.'
Sally Dalzell runs her wardrobe consultancy, Change of A-Dress, with a
partner. The Christmas run-up is their busiest time. 'We lived abroad until
quite recently so I am happy to have a traditional English Christmas in
London. After my three children, aged nine to 12, come home from boarding
school I want to devote myself to them so time for me is bottom of the list.
We will also have my two grown-up stepchildren staying.
'On Christmas morning it's straight into turkey-cooking and present-opening.
I like to look smart although not hugely dressy. Relaxation and comfort come
above all else; I get hot cooking. A loose cashmere sweater and leggings
would be great. I can add a velvet scarf and a coat for church, swap the
leggings for satin pyjama trousers at home. I don't like Christmassy
colours. I would put the outfit together from pieces I already owned.'
Anastasia Alexander, an American, started her Aroma Therapeutics business in
Britain two years ago. It is expanding rapidly in the US and Europe. 'This
is a very busy time both at work and socially, so I have to pre-plan. In
America, Thanksgiving is the family celebration; Christmas is party time. So
for breakfast I would probably still be wearing an evening dress. Here we
prefer to be in the country with my three stepchildren, our 14-month-old
daughter, Alexia, and our nanny.
'I am very organised with clothes, adding a few pieces each season to update
the classics. I like wearably avant-garde designers: Dolce e Gabbana, Romeo
Gigli, Dries van Noten. I have already planned my Christmas wardrobe. In the
morning I will go riding and then have a leisurely breakfast. I would choose
something country-style but festive, like a velvet waistcoat and trousers.'
LUNCH
Ewa Lewis, social editor of The Tatler, is Polish by birth. She has a family
house party for 14 in Gloucestershire, for which preparations have long been
under way and there will be a mix of traditions.
'In Poland, Christmas Eve is the big night so we have a formal dinner with
caviar, borscht and lots of fish. Christmas day is relaxed - presents,
church, champagne, then turkey for lunch. The staff have a holiday so I give
everyone, especially my children, aged 15 and 13, jobs to do. I co-ordinate
it all and cook.
'I don't pre-plan what to wear at home during Christmas but I am very
organised. I shop early in the season from my favourite designers - St
Laurent, Tomasz Starzewski, Bruce Oldfield, Laura B - with festivities in
mind. Knowing that a country Christmas will include sporty and very dressy
occasions, I take down what I need. For any lunch out over the holiday I
think a suit in rich velvet is right; at home I might wear a soft trouser
suit.'
Lady Charles Spencer Churchill, aka interior decorator Jane Churchill, will
go with her three sons, aged from 23 to 11, to the family country home -
Blenheim.
She says: 'Christmas lunch is a fairly informal, family occasion and I think
a suit is right. I particularly like Armani's - they are soft and classic
yet smart. Pastels are very becoming and show off jewellery well. I'm lucky,
I don't have to stuff the turkey so I can relax and enjoy the whole
atmosphere. For the evening I would change to something more formal.'
Alessandra Rossi is a Milanesa, married to a London-based Italian investment
banker. She loves entertaining.
'I shop in September, with Christmas in mind, at St Laurent and Gucci. I
never leave it till the last minute because nothing will be left in my size.
I plan what to take but our family lunch is sporty rather than dressy. The
men wear a tie, the women something with red in it. I think a printed silk
shirt and suede jeans would look relaxed but festive.'
Paola Tholstrup is a mix of Italian, Polish and German but was brought up in
Switzerland. Her husband, Mogens, owns London restaurant Daphne's and they
have a 20-month-old daughter.
'I don't exactly pre-plan my clothes, but I take a selection that I've
bought over the years from my favourite shops - Browns, Joseph, Ronit
Zilhka, Jil Sander. I am not interested enough to look for a specific
Christmas dress. For the Christmas Eve dinner I would take a black cocktail
dress; for lunch something cosy but smart like a knitted dress spruced up
with gilt buttons.'
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P23   Apparel and Other Textile Products.
    P56   Apparel and Accessory Stores.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page V
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-3987</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELLBEAB3FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941210
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  10 DEC 94 / Seasonal chart-topper retains selling power
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By ALICE RAWSTHORN
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
This time last year Take That, the teen idols, took on Mr Blobby - and lost.
This year East 17 and Mariah Carey are slugging it out against the Mighty
Morph-n Power Rangers for the top slot in the 1994 Christmas pop charts.
A Christmas number one not only wins the dubious accolade of becoming the
year's office party anthem but is also extremely lucrative. Usually twice as
many singles are sold in the two or three weeks before Christmas than in the
same period at any other time of the year.
The competition for the top of this year's Christmas chart is hotter than
ever. The music industry has rebounded from the recession and had a good
year. Record companies have been rushing out seasonal releases in the hope
that their artists can cash in on the pre-Christmas spree.
Mr Graham Sharpe, who runs a book on the Christmas number one for William
Hill, the bookmaker, said: 'This is one of the most exciting Christmas
charts ever. There are lots of Christmas singles out there and there'll be a
real race for number one.'
The phenomenon of the Christmas number one dates from 1955, when Dickie
Valentine's Christmas Alphabet topped the charts. Harry Belafonte continued
the tradition two years later with Mary's Boy Child.
There were no truly Christmassy number ones in the 1960s. But the festive
spirit revived amid the kitsch ethos of the early 1970s when Slade hit the
top spot with Merry Christmas Everybody in 1973 followed by Mud with Lonely
This Christmas in 1974.
The 1970s also marked the emergence of Christmas hits as a significant
source of sales. Queen's Bohemian Rhapsody and Mull of Kintyre by Paul
McCartney and Wings topped the Christmas charts when they were released in
1975 and 1977 respectively. Each went on to sell 2m copies.
They were out-sold by Do They Know It's Christmas?, the Band Aid charity
single which sold 3m copies and scored two Christmas number ones, in 1984
and 1989.
More recent Christmas hits have had more modest sales. According to the
British Phonographic Industry the music market peaked in 1979, when 89m
singles were sold. The singles sector reached its nadir in 1992, when sales
fell to 53m due to the recession and the decline in the number of teenagers
 -the chief purchasers of singles.
The market has since revived as the recession has ended and the teenage
population has started to grow. The BPI estimates that singles sales rose to
Pounds 95m, or 62m units, in the 12 months to September, a 12 per cent
increase from the same period last year.
This bodes well for Christmas. Even in the lean years it has been the
busiest time of the year for the market as many people who do not normally
buy records pick up singles for parties or presents.
CIN, the market research consultancy which compiles the singles chart,
estimates that a Christmas chart-topper sells between 150,000 and 200,000
copies a week, compared with between 50,000 and 100,000 a week at any other
time of the year. Christmas hits have the chance of repeat sales if they are
re-released in subsequent years.
As a result record companies invest heavily in the Christmas market.
Columbia, a subsidiary of the Sony group, recorded its seasonal offering,
Mariah Carey's All I Want For Christmas Is You, in February.
Her single went straight into the charts at number six last week and might
dislodge East 17, the current number one, in the new chart when it is
unveiled tomorrow evening.
East 17 is still ahead in William Hill's books, with odds of 6-4, compared
with 3-1 for Mariah Carey. But the Power Rangers are steaming up from the
rear with odds of 9-2 as they try to follow in Mr Blobby's footsteps as the
1994 gimmick ticket.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3652 Prerecorded Records and Tapes.
    P5735 Record and Prerecorded Tape Stores.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>MKTS  Sales.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 7
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4002</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELLBEABOFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941210
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  10 DEC 94 / CBI chief urges independent Bank
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
The chancellor's decision this week to raise base rates reinforced the need
for a fully-independent Bank of England, Mr Howard Davies, director-general
of the Confederation of British Industry, said yesterday.
Mr Davies noted the statement on Thursday by Mr Eddie George, the Bank
governor, that politics had been irrelevant in his recommendation of the
rate increase but added: 'It looks as though companies are being made to pay
for a lack of political management.'
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6011 Federal Reserve Banks.
    P8611 Business Associations.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 6
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4047</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELLBEAAFFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941210
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  10 DEC 94 / World News in Brief: Probation for baby snatcher
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Julie Kelley, 22, who abducted newborn baby Abbie Humphries from a
Nottingham hospital, was put on probation for three years at Nottingham
crown court. Miss Kelley, who is pregnant, was ordered to undergo
psycho-therapeutic treatment after the birth of her child.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9211 Courts.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4160</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELIDCAESFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941209
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  09 DEC 94 / UK Company News: Travis Perkins sells subsidiary for Pounds
11m
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Travis Perkins, the building materials group, has sold its Kennedys Garden
Centres subsidiary for Pounds 10.8m cash in a management buy-out.
A new company has been formed to make the acquisition. Mr George Bullivant,
managing director of Kennedys, will be managing director of the new company,
which will keep its original name.
The consideration is subject to a revision of up to Pounds 1m, to be decided
on completion.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Travis Perkins.
    Kennedys Garden Centres.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P5031 Lumber, Plywood and Millwork.
    P5261 Retail Nurseries and Garden Stores.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Buy-in &amp; Buy-out.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 21
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4204</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELIDCADKFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941209
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  09 DEC 94 / Technology (Worth Watching): Switched off for personal
messages
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By VANESSA HOULDER
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Using a computer to handle voice and fax messages often means leaving it
switched on even when the user is out.
Martignoni Electronics, a Swiss communication company, has launched a
personal message centre, which stores fax and telephone messages, regardless
of whether the PC is switched on. The Spiderman, which stores 20 pages of
fax or 60 minutes of voice messages, costs Pounds 349.
Martignoni Electronics: Switzerland, tel 1273 1111; fax 1273 3700.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>CHZ  Switzerland, West Europe.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3661 Telephone and Telegraph Apparatus.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>TECH  Products &amp; Product use.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 14
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4213</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELIDCADBFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941209
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  09 DEC 94 / People: Non-executive directors
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Gary Sturgess, former cabinet secretary and director general of the Cabinet
Office in New South Wales and principal of Sturgess Australia, and Sir John
Whitehead, former British ambassador to Japan, at SERCO GROUP.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Serco Group.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P7372 Prepackaged Software.
    P7389 Business Services, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 14
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4215</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELIDCAC9FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941209
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  09 DEC 94 / People: Non-executive directors
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By WILLIAM HALL
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Jerry Brand, 37, who runs the privately-owned Brand Group, a fast-growing
contract caterer, has taken a step closer to fulfilling his stock market
ambitions by recruiting his first independent non-executive director -
Stirling Gallacher.
Gallacher, 62, was managing director of Gardner Merchant Caterers, the
industry leader, in the mid-1970s and went on to do the same job at
Sutcliffe Catering, another of the big three UK contract caters. He retired
as chairman of Sutcliffe in 1992 after Granada had bought the company.
Brand started his own catering company in 1988 and annual turnover has grown
from Pounds 670,000 to Pounds 30m in the current year, with Pounds 40m
budgeted for next year. Brand expects to make pre-tax profits of Pounds
600,000 in 1994 and is hoping to get his company floated on the stock market
by 1996. He says that he is looking for an additional non-executive director
with financial experience.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Brand Group.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P5812 Eating Places.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 14
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4284</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELIDCABCFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941209
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  09 DEC 94 / Ad agencies up in India
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By SHIRAZ SIDHVA
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   NEW DELHI
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Indian advertising agencies boosted billings 37.4 per cent in 1993-94,
according to an annual survey conducted by A&amp;M, the country's leading
marketing and advertising magazine.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>INZ  India, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P7311 Advertising Agencies.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>MGMT  Management &amp; Marketing.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 4
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4482</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELHD0AC3FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941208
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  08 DEC 94 / After The VAT Vote: Pre-paid cash to be returned
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
British Gas customers who pre-paid bills to avoid the planned rise in value
added tax will have their money returned in the next few days, the company
said last night.
Eastern Group, the biggest regional power company, also said it would be
making immediate repayments.
British Gas said it did not know how many of its 18m customers had paid in
advance. Eastern Group said yesterday that about 100 of its customers were
affected. 'We know who they are and we are putting a cheque in the post
today,' it said.
East Midlands Electricity and Southern Electric said they would refund
customers who wrote to them.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>British Gas.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P4923 Gas Transmission and Distribution.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COSTS  Service costs &amp; Service prices.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 14
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4549</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELHD0AA8FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941208
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  08 DEC 94 / S Africa to write off debt from Namibia
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By REUTER
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   JOHANNESBURG
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
South Africa is to write off a R700m (Pounds 126m) debt owed by its former
colony Namibia even though it is trying to win foreign aid and investment to
help it rebuild from the ravages of apartheid.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>ZAZ  South Africa, Africa.
    NAZ  Namibia, Africa.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9721 International Affairs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 4
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4657</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELGCWAFNFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941207
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  07 DEC 94 / UK Company News: Marley US deal
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
General Shale Products, the US subsidiary of Marley, has acquired two
concrete block manufacturing plants from Bristol Steel for Dollars 3.8m
(Pounds 2.31m) in cash.
The acquisitions, Bristol Concrete Products Corpn and Tri-State Concrete
Company, are situated in Bristol, Virginia, and Kingsport, Tennessee, close
to two of General Shale's existing concrete block operations.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>General Shale Products Corp.
    Bristol Steel.
    Bristol Concrete Products Corp.
    Tri-State Concrete.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
    USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3271 Concrete Block and Brick.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Disposals.
    COMP  Mergers &amp; acquisitions.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 30
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4736</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELGCWADGFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941207
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  07 DEC 94 / Arts: A Christmas Carol - Theatre
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By ALASTAIR MACAULAY
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
To see Charles Dickens's A Christmas Carol onstage is to know again, with a
frisson of joy, how theatrical its author's instincts were.
What, I wonder, would he have made of the coup de theatre with which the
Royal Shakespeare Company's new version of A Christmas Carol opens? The
panoramic view of London in dark silhouette, dominated by the dome of St
Paul's, lifts yards into the sky - and, from the blackness beneath, there
emerge people, also in black: in Bible black, indeed, for Marley's funeral.
I hope Dickens would have marvelled at all this, and at much that follows in
Ian Judge's staging of John Mortimer's new adaptation.
This Christmas Carol, following the haunting RSC precedent of Trevor Nunn's
Nicholas Nickleby, proceeds on three main levels: as a series of stage
pictures, as a stage elucidation of Dickens's text, and as a collage of
Victorian Christmas music. Sometimes the three come thrillingly together: as
when Scrooge snuffs out the Spirit of Christmas Past. We see the conical
snuffing-cap pushing the Spirit down into (and through) the ground; we
follow Scrooge's exhausting travail much as Dickens described it; and
meanwhile the scene is watched by a chorus of Victorians in black, who sing
'Hark the herald angels sing' with warning fierceness. The melodramatic
excitement, the psychological intensity, the sense of Christmas as a
jubilantly lyrical experience that is being threatened by Scrooge - all
these are there together.
Visually, the production is consistently excellent - thanks in particular to
John Gunter's set, Deirdre Clancy's costumes, and Nigel Levings's lighting.
Verbally, Mortimer's text is first-rate; he is plainly in love with Dickens
as both sound and sense. And so are most of Judge's RSC actors, most of them
playing several roles each. A pity that he lets them make too little of some
lines (Scrooge 'carried his own low temperature always about with him') and
some episodes (Belle breaking off her engagement to a younger Scrooge). But
where the production is more frequently flawed is with Nigel Hess's music.
Most of the onstage singing is weak, but the taped music and orchestrations
are worse. The difference a few live instruments - - and less amplification
 -would make] As an arranger, he could have struck more gold from his
material; but since his material is mainly the classic Christmas carols we
all know, the perfect Dickensian fusion of generosity and sentiment is
achieved now and then.
Clive Francis is a first-rate Scrooge, an antique crustacean who manages to
glow friskily once he learns to drop his shell. Paul Greenwood and Polly
James do good work as the tender Cratchit parents, as do Philip Quast and
Sara Weymouth as Scrooge's laughing nephew and his wife, Cherry Morris and
Peter Warnock as the bubbling old Fezziwigs. The Spirit of Christmas Present
(John Kane) is too bombastic, and Christmas past (Stephen Jean) too mild;
they should be Virgil to Scrooge's Dante. Marley's ghost - so plainly
modelled on Hamlet's papa - is over-miked and under-chained.
But the 18-foot Christmas Yet To Come, hooded and cloaked like a Grim Reaper
with only two skeletal claws visible, is splendid. The party scenes are all
infectious. And the finale, with snow falling through the hovering Christmas
trees and rooftops onto the cast, whose black attire is now illumined by
scarlet winter scarves, is ideal.
Barbican Theatre, EC2
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P7922 Theatrical Producers and Services.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 19
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4849</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELGCWAABFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941207
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  07 DEC 94 / World News in Brief: Death sentence for anti-abortionist
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Former church minister and anti-abortionist Paul Hill was sentenced to death
in Florida for murdering an abortion clinic doctor and his escort.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9211 Courts.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  People.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4930</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELFDIAFKFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941206
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 DEC 94 / International Company News: Matsushita to use IBM chip
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By WILLIAM DAWKINS
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   TOKYO
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Matsushita, Japan's largest maker of consumer electronic products, yesterday
became the fourth Japanese company to adopt International Business Machines'
microprocessor technology for multimedia products.
Matsushita has signed a letter of intent with the US computer group jointly
to develop multimedia products using IBM's PowerPC chip, a fast 64-bit
microprocessor for personal computers.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Matsushita Electric Industrial.
    International Business Machines Corp.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>JPZ  Japan, Asia.
    USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3674 Semiconductors and Related Devices.
    P3571 Electronic Computers.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Strategic links &amp; Joint venture.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 26
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4934</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELFDIAFFFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941206
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 DEC 94 / UK Company News: Edinburgh Nw Tiger
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Edinburgh New Tiger Trust, which invests in quoted smaller companies in
emerging Asian countries, reported a 7 per cent fall in net asset value in
the 9 1/2 months period since its January launch.
Net asset value at October 31 was 44.75p, against 48.19p on January 14.
After-tax revenue for the period came to Pounds 1.34m and earnings per share
were 0.4782p. There is a final dividend of 0.4p.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Edinburgh New Tiger Trust.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6726 Investment Offices, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>FIN  Interim results.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 24
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-4978</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELFDIAD6FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941206
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 DEC 94 / Observer: Wrong numbers
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Now that UK phone company Mercury is sacking loads of staff, will it bring
in redundancy counsellors for One-2-One sessions?
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Mercury Communications.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P99   Nonclassifiable Establishments.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 19
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5013</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELFDIAC7FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941206
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 DEC 94 / People: Bodies Politic
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Keith Birch, formerly head of optical metrology at the National Physical
Laboratory, has been appointed executive secretary of the BRITISH
MEASUREMENT AND TESTING ASSOCIATION; John Wilson, founder secretary, becomes
executive assistant.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9651 Regulation of Miscellaneous Commercial Sectors.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 13
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5015</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELFDIAC5FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941206
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 DEC 94 / People: Bodies Politic
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
William Day has been appointed director of the OPPORTUNITY TRUST which funds
revolving-loan schemes in developing countries.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9611 Administration of General Economic Programs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 13
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5024</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELFDIACWFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941206
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 DEC 94 / Management (The Growing Business): Getting value out of your
valuer - In a Nutshell
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Don't employ unqualified people to give advice on rating matters following
the latest uniform business rate revaluation to be announced early next
year. So says the Institute of Revenues Rating and Valuation, which
represents public- and private-sector staff involved in local taxation.
If the institute is to be believed, the UK is full of 'bogus rating
consultants'. The institute's advice is to wait. Lists of valuations will be
published by the Valuation Office Agency early in 1995 showing new rateable
values that will come in next April.
In the meantime, Business Rates: Your Guide is available for Pounds 5.99
from the Institute of Revenues Rating and Valuation. Tel 071 831 3505.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P8611 Business Associations.
    P2741 Miscellaneous Publishing.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
    TECH  Products &amp; Product use.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 12
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5036</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELFDIACKFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941206
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 DEC 94 / M0 growth falls back to 7.1% in November
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By GILLIAN TETT, Economics Staff
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
The rate of annual growth in M0, the narrowest measure of money supply, fell
back in November, Bank of England figures yesterday showed.
Measured on a seasonally adjusted basis, M0 grew 7.1 per cent in the year to
November.
This was lower than in October and September when M0 grew by 7.3 per cent
and 7.2 per cent respectively.
However, the annual growth rate was slightly higher than the market had
expected and remains well outside the government's target monitoring range
of 0 to 4 per cent.
With the markets dogged by speculation about whether Mr Kenneth Clarke, the
chancellor, and Mr Eddie George, governor of the Bank of England, will raise
interest rates when they meet tomorrow, analysts were yesterday divided
about the implications of the data.
M0 has traditionally been taken by the Bank of England as an important
inflation indicator. However the Bank and Treasury have recently moved away
from using monetary aggregates to set interest policy, not least because M0
has diverged from retail sales and inflation trends this year.
Ms Helen MacFarlane, economist at brokers Hoare Govett, said that the
slowdown in M0 should 'move it down the authorities' risk list'.
'Month-on-month M0 growth seems to be moving back more in line with retail
sales. If true, this implies that November may have been a poor month for
retailers, although this may reflect prices rather than volumes,' she said.
Mr Andrew Cates of brokers UBS yesterday argued that the M0 data suggested
that a there was a strong case for a base rate rise this month.
'The current growth in M0 clearly gives cause for concern about future
inflation,' he said, pointing out that in spite of the fall in the annual
growth rate of M0 in November the three month annualised rate remained
strong, running at 7.2 per cent in November, compared with 5.3 per cent in
August.
The rate of annual growth in notes and coins, which represent 99 per cent of
M0, grew by 6.8 per cent in the year to November, compared with an annual
growth rate of 7.1 per cent in October.
The Bank of England yesterday said the measure for broad money supply M4
grew by 3.9 per cent in the year to October.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9311 Finance, Taxation, and Monetary Policy.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>ECON  Economic Indicators.
    CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 10
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5042</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELFDIACEFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941206
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 DEC 94 / West End star
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
The Christmas tree in London's Trafalgar Square, which was donated by
Norway, is decorated yesterday amid the spray of the square's fountains
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P99   Nonclassifiable Establishments.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 9
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5067</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELFDIABPFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941206
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 DEC 94 / World Trade News: Thorn Transit Systems International -
Contracts &amp; ventures
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By Foreign Staff
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   LONDON
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Thorn Transit Systems International of the UK, will be awarded a contract
worth about HKDollars 200m (Dollars 26m) to design, manufacture, install and
commission an automatic fare collection system for the airport railway in
Hong Kong. The 34km railway will provide two separate services, a fast
passenger link to the new airport and a domestic service called the Lantau
Line.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Thorn Transit Systems International.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>HKZ  Hong Kong, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3578 Calculating and Accounting Equipment.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>MKTS  Contracts.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 6
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5078</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELFDIABEFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941206
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  06 DEC 94 / Pena visit to Taipei steps up US links
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By LAURA TYSON
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   TAIPEI
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Mr Federico Pena, US transportation secretary, yesterday called on Taiwan's
foreign ministry, the first US cabinet official to do so in 15 years in a
sign of Washington support for the island's democratic reforms and
recognition of its growing economic clout.
Mr Pena visited Mr Fredrick Chien, foreign minister, stepping up bilateral
ties despite previous objections by China. The meeting was significant as
Beijing tolerates economic ties but frowns on those carrying diplomatic
import.
The Clinton administration official is visiting Taiwan at the invitation of
the US-Taiwan Economic Council, a private business organisation. He is to
meet Taiwanese President Lee Teng-hui, Mr Lien Chan, the premier, and other
officials.
Washington severed diplomatic ties with Taipei in 1979 in favour of Beijing.
The US has since maintained strong but low-profile informal ties with
Taiwan.
On Saturday, Taiwan held elections for provincial governor for the first
time and the first elections in three decades for city mayors. Pressure from
the US Congress, supportive of Taiwan's democratisation, led the
administration to upgrade ties in September, after the first review of
Taiwan policy since 1979.
Mr Pena is only the second US cabinet official to visit Taiwan since 1979.
Ms Carla Hills, then US trade representative, came to the island in 1992 but
did not meet the foreign minister.
Mr Pena yesterday met American Chamber of Commerce members to discuss
infrastructure projects in Taiwan. A high-speed railway, urban mass transit
systems and a fourth nuclear power plant are among projects planned or under
way. He also met Mr Vincent Siew, chairman of Taiwan's planning ministry.
Today he is due to witness a Dollars 226m (Pounds 141m) contract signing by
Westinghouse Electric of the US and Taiwan's environmental protection agency
to build two solid-waste incinerators on the island.
See World Stock Markets
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>TWZ  Taiwan, Asia.
    USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9721 International Affairs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 4
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5228</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELECYAB5FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941205
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  05 DEC 94 / Media Futures: Film empire strikes back - Games are feeling
the force of Hollywood
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By ALICE RAWSTHORN
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Any Star Wars buffs who ever dreamt of fighting the Rebel Alliance by flying
an Imperial starfighter under Darth Vader's command can now act out their
fantasies by buying TIE Fighter, one of the dozens of new computer games on
sale this Christmas.
TIE Fighter is the latest launch from Lucas Arts, the games subsidiary
created in the early 1980s by George Lucas, director of Star Wars, at his
state-of-the-art entertainment laboratory at San Rafael, California.
Mr Lucas, who dropped out of the Hollywood mainstream over a decade ago to
pursue his passion for technology, was a pioneer of the use of movie themes
and characters in games. His Star Wars games often feature at the top of the
computer games charts and the Hollywood studios are now racing to follow
Lucas Arts into the games sphere. Time Warner earlier this year acquired
Renegade, a games software house. New Line, the film company owned by Ted
Turner, the new-media mogul, recently formed a Dollars 30m (Pounds 18m)
joint venture with France's Havas to develop a global games business. Even
record companies are muscling into the market. Motown, the music label owned
by PolyGram, recently launched a Motown Games subsidiary.
The next convert to the games sphere is mooted to be Walt Disney, which is
expected this week to announce plans for the formation of a new interactive
entertainment division. Disney, like other studios, presently licenses its
characters for use in games devised by other companies such as Sega and
Nintendo, the Japanese games specialists.
The catalyst for Hollywood's sudden surge of interest in computer games is
the emergence of the new generation of disc-based games. The games market
has since the early 1980s been dominated by the 16-bit cartridge consoles
made by Sega and Nintendo.
For the past year or so the market has been moving towards disc-based games
played on home computers and multimedia machines that are able to play
CD-Roms, or interactive discs. Lucas Arts and other companies have already
made the most of the enhanced qualities of disc medium to create more
sophisticated games. They will be able to reach new levels of sophistication
with the next wave of change - the launch of the 32-bit and 64-bit
disc-based games, that are now being introduced in Japan and will come out
next year in the US and Europe.
These games are much more powerful than the old 16-bit cartridge consoles.
They have the capacity to create cinematic sounds and images that are
perfect vehicles for the characters and plots of Hollywood movies.
'There's no doubt that CD-Roms and the new games formats could become a
phenomenal growth market,' says Michael Lynne, president of New Line in New
York. 'All the attributes of a motion picture will soon be available on a
computer screen, so we can apply our skills to create games and informative
'edutainment' products.' New Line, like the other studios, plans to become
more aggressive at adapting its movie concepts into games. However, Randy
Komisar, president of Lucas Arts, suspects that Hollywood may have
underestimated the complexity of the games market.
'There is scope to use the techniques of movie-making in a game - we do it
all the time,' he says. 'But film is a linear medium and a game is a virtual
experience. If you take the content of a movie to use in a game, it must be
developed so that it is exciting and engaging in an interactive context.'
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Lucas Arts Entertainment.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3944 Games, Toys, and Children's Vehicles.
    P7372 Prepackaged Software.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>TECH  Products &amp; Product use.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 11
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5256</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELECYABDFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941205
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  05 DEC 94 / BT survey finds teleworking rise
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Nearly 30 per cent of companies have employees who work from home or who
plan to shortly, a study published today by British Telecommunications has
found.
The biggest growth in teleworking is in the media, where a third of
employees spend time working from home, and business consultancy, where 31
per cent do so. Many have started in the past six months.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P7389 Business Services, NEC.
    P8732 Commercial Nonphysical Research.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 6
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5263</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELECYAA6FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941205
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  05 DEC 94 / BT survey finds teleworking rise
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Nearly 30 per cent of companies have employees who work from home or who
plan to shortly, a study published today by British Telecommunications has
found.
The biggest growth in teleworking is in the media, where a third of
employees spend time working from home, and business consultancy, where 31
per cent do so. Many have started in the past six months.
The survey was carried out by NOP between June and September this year with
2,813 business interviews.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P7389 Business Services, NEC.
    P8732 Commercial Nonphysical Research.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 6
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5304</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELECYAE6FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941203
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  03 DEC 94 / Derivative growth could hamstring Fed
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
The growth in derivatives, combined with other global market changes, could
hamper the Federal Reserve's ability to contain a financial crisis, Ms Susan
Phillips, Federal Reserve governor, said.
Report, Page 2
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6221 Commodity Contracts Brokers, Dealers.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>MKTS  Market data.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5567</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELBDWAF6FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941202
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  02 DEC 94 / Commodities and Agriculture: Commodity fund seeks uses for
unwanted support money
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By FRANCES WILLIAMS
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   GENEVA
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
The Common Fund for Commodities is to draw up proposals for a programme of
technical assistance to aid commodity producers to trade their wares
efficiently. The move follows strong pressure on the Amsterdam-based fund to
find a good use for some Dollars 20m, left untouched because it is earmarked
for commodity price support operations that have never materialised.
Australia, Canada and New Zealand have withdrawn from the fund and others
have threatened to follow suit if a solution is not found soon.
At its annual governing council meeting earlier this week, the fund's 105
members agreed to prepare a technical assistance programme that would enable
commodity producers to take better advantage of new trading opportunities
opened up by the Uruguay Round global trade accords.
Mr Bruno de Vuyst, council secretary, says the focus will be on helping
countries to organise efficient national and regional commodity exchanges,
improving warehousing and advising on relevant legislation.
Fund members also agreed this week to come up with new ideas for employing
the Dollars 71m of capital contributions in the so-called 'first account',
including possible amendment of the 1980 treaty setting up the fund. This
requires the surplus income from the first account (after covering Dollars
3m-a-year administrative costs) to be used for loans to cover buffer stock
operations.
Since the treaty was signed, price stabilisation accords have fallen out of
favour. Only one commodity pact with buffer stock arrangements - on natural
rubber - now remains and its members have shown no interest in using 'first
account' resources.
The fund, which began operations in 1989, has also come under fire for the
slow start of its 'second account' programme, which uses voluntary
contributions from donors to help finance commodity development projects.
However, 27 projects worth Dollars 60m have now been approved (21 of them in
the past two years) with the fund contributing Dollars 23.6m. The remaining
cash has been raised from other national and international organisations.
In a less encouraging development, the governing board failed this week to
elect a new managing director after votes split equally between the two
leading candidates, Mr Dany Ghekiere of Belgium and Mr Ernest Leung of the
Philippines.
The present managing director, Mr Budi Hartantyo of Indonesia, is to serve
for a further year while countries come up with fresh nominations.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>CHZ  Switzerland, West Europe.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9611 Administration of General Economic Programs.
    P01   Agricultural Production-Crops.
    P10   Metal Mining.
    P12   Coal Mining.
    P13   Oil and Gas Extraction.
    P14   Nonmetallic Minerals, Ex Fuels.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
    RES  Capital expenditures.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 27
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5649</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELBDWADVFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941202
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  02 DEC 94 / Observer: PED-cure
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Whitehall boffins have added another acronym to their extensive lexicon. PED
 -preliminary exploratory dialogue - is the official euphemism for talks
with Sinn Fein, set to start next week. Presumably we will know progress is
being made when the boffins start referring to 'ED' and eventually 'D'.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P99   Nonclassifiable Establishments.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 15
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5686</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELBDWACSFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941202
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  02 DEC 94 / People: Bodies politic
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Gerald Dennis, chairman of Alexandra Workwear and Domino Printing Sciences,
has been appointed a joint vice-chairman of GREAT BRITAIN SPORTS COUNCIL.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P8699 Membership Organizations, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 11
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5914</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELAD8AD7FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941201
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  01 DEC 94 / Observer: Naked Ken
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Meanwhile, the prize for the most imaginative piece of post-Budget
scribbling must go to Credit Lyonnais Laing for its 26-page glossy booklet -
Kenneth: his new Budget. No one has tried harder to sell a boring Budget to
a wider audience. Starting with a flattering portrait of the chancellor, the
dust cover promises that Kenneth reveals all: how his spending disorder was
found out; how the markets forced him into a loveless marriage with Eddie;
how his private conversations were later revealed in the press, etc.
Plaudits for the book include: 'It's hard to believe it's all his own work'
(Norman Lamont), to 'Right up to the last page you don't know how much tax
you are going to be paying' (Crime Writers' Guild). However, Labour's Gordon
Brown summed it up best - 'A difficult one to follow.'
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P2731 Book Publishing.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 23
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5915</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELAD8AD6FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941201
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  01 DEC 94 / Observer: Truth will out
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Maybe it was post-Budget exhaustion. But Kenneth Clarke rather gave the game
away during a briefing for economic hacks at the Treasury yesterday. Asked
how many new jobs his Budget measures would create, the chancellor
responded: 'I haven't yet calculated how many votes will be created.'
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9311 Finance, Taxation, and Monetary Policy.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 23
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5941</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELAD8ADGFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941201
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  01 DEC 94 / People: Yorkshire Water
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
David Brimblecombe, formerly a director and company secretary of Yorkshire
Chemicals, has been appointed deputy company secretary of YORKSHIRE WATER.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Yorkshire Water.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P4941 Water Supply.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 20
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-5945</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELAD8ADCFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941201
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  01 DEC 94 / People: BOC
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
BOC, the industrial gases group, has moved quickly to plug the gap left by
Phil Aiken's surprise move to be chief executive of BTR Nylex in Australia.
Barry Beecroft, 48, who has been with BOC for 26 years, has been appointed
managing director of the group's European gas business, which has annual
sales of over Pounds 500m.
Beecroft, a chemical engineer, is currently regional director of BOC's gas
business in the South Pacific and managing director of its Australian gas
operation. He was formerly operations director of BOC's UK gases business.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>BOC Group.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P2813 Industrial Gases.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 20
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6006</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELAD8ABNFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941201
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  01 DEC 94 / World Trade News: Peugeot to assemble cars in Pakistan
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By AFX
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   KARACHI
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Automobiles Peugeot of France yesterday said it planned to assemble diesel
cars in Pakistan from 1996 with Pakistani carmaker Worldwide Motors, AFX
reports from Karachi. Mr Yves Barbe, Peugeot senior executive
vice-president, said talks were at an 'advanced stage'. Peugeot intends to
manufacture 10,000 cars there each year.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Automobiles Peugeot.
    Worldwide Motors.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>FRZ  France, EC.
    PKZ  Pakistan, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3711 Motor Vehicles and Car Bodies.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Strategic links &amp; Joint venture.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 7
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6073</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELAD8AILFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941130
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  30 NOV 94 / Dole meets Claes before Bosnia talks
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Robert Dole, the US Senate Republican leader, meets Nato secretary general
Willy Claes yesterday before talks in Brussels. Dole later called for an end
to the arms embargo against Bosnia's Moslems as a way of putting pressure on
the Serbs to agree a peace plan.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>BEZ  Belgium, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9721 International Affairs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  People.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
International Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6181</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK3EKAGSFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941130
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  30 NOV 94 / Budget 94 (Government Statements): New capital allowance
rules
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Changes are planned to the rules on capital allowances to encourage the
investment of private capital in roads as part of the government's private
finance initiative.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9311 Finance, Taxation, and Monetary Policy.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>GOVT  Government News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 45
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6269</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK3EKAECFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941130
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  30 NOV 94 / Budget 94 (Tax): Cigarette tax rises but beer stays put -
Tobacco/Drink
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By MOTOKO RICH
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
The chancellor yesterday fulfilled his commitment to a 3 per cent real
increase in tax on tobacco to support the government's aim of reducing
smoking.
From 6pm last night, tax on each packet of 20 cigarettes rose by 10p and the
chancellor promised that duty on other tobacco products would rise by a
similar proportion.
However, the tax on beer, table wine and spirits was left unchanged as the
chancellor responded to complaints from the drinks industry about duties and
the increase in cross-Channel shopping and smuggling.
The chancellor reduced the duty on fortified wine by 13p per bottle and on
sparkling wine by 27p to bring the two duties into line with each other.
Mr Kenneth Clarke's action on beer was largely expected as a Treasury select
committee last week rejected a call by brewers for beer duty to be halved to
curb cross-Channel imports.
In his speech, Mr Clarke said cross-border shopping and smuggling had 'meant
a loss of duty to the exchequer'. He said that 'no chancellor can remain
unmoved in the face of this, but neither can any chancellor simply adopt
popular measures to cut taxes on alcohol that would threaten the revenue'.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P208  Beverages.
    P21   Tobacco Products.
    P9311 Finance, Taxation, and Monetary Policy.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>GOVT  Taxes.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 23
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6315</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK3EKAC2FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941130
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  30 NOV 94 / Mitsubishi's extended family
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By WILLIAM DAWKINS
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Mitsubishi, the most tightly interwoven of Japan's keiretsu corporate
families, is a classic example of how formerly cosy group ties are being
subjected to market forces.
It is an empire of 216,000 employees, prominent in businesses ranging from
banking to beer, shipping and shipbuilding, property, oil, aerospace and
textiles. On average, the 29 companies at the heart of the group hold 38 per
cent of each other's shares, above the average for keiretsu corporate
families.
Mitsubishi companies exchange more directors than do other keiretsu and have
a long record of rallying member companies from different parts of the group
to co-operate on projects, one of the main competitive advantages of the
keiretsu system.
Tokyo's business district, Marunouchi, is dominated by the headquarters of
15 Mitsubishi group companies, known as Mitsubishi Village, a visual symbol
of their central role in Japan's industrial establishment.
Intra-group co-operation can be taken less for granted since the on-set of
recession in 1991 prompted management across the group to place
profitability, rather than gaining market share, as the prime objective,
says Mr Masayoshi Hayashikawa, general manager of planning at Mitsubishi
Corporation, the trading company near the heart of the group.
This new approach is best illustrated by the recent decision of Nippon
Yusen, a shipper in the group, to buy South Korean ships for the first time,
rather than from its usual supplier, Mitsubishi Heavy Industries. The yen's
rise has made Japanese shipbuilding costs 30 per cent higher than South
Korea's. 'A mutually beneficial relationship in steel and ships? That is a
thing of the past,' says Mr Tsuda Yoshida, managing director of Mitsubishi
Heavy Industries.
Similarly, MHI recently decided to use Nissho Iwai, a member of the Sanwa
keiretsu, to sell its ownheavy machinery in Indonesia.
Mitsubishi group members also have no qualms about declining requests from
Mitsubishi Estate to take space in one of the world's most expensive
buildings, the under-occupied Y270bn, 80-floor, Landmark Tower in Yokohama.
However, family members still close ranks when business interests or
opportunities are at stake.
Landmark Tower, for example, is a classic example of the kind of mistimed
property development that has brought many developers to their knees. The
project was started by Mitsubishi Estate just before the spectacular
collapse in inflated asset prices four years ago and completed in July last
year, in the depth of the recession.
An independent company might have been forced to dump the project. Yet
Mitsubishi Estate was able to carry on, confident that Mitsubishi Bank would
continue funding the project through good times and bad. Landmark Tower may
be a white elephant today, but even the most critical property analysts
believe that any company that can afford to continue owning the tower will
end up, in a few years, with one of the finest assets in the domestic
property market.
But perhaps the most enduring quality of the keiretsu system, says Mr
Hayashikawa, is its ability to pass information fast around the corporate
family.
In Mitsubishi's case, the vehicle for this is the so-called 'Friday Club' at
which the bosses of the top 29 member companies meet for a chat over lunch
on the second Friday of each month, on the top floor of the Mitsubishi
Building in Marunouchi.
It is at this gathering that intelligence can be shared, paving the way for
group companies to work together. An example of how this team-work can still
pay dividends is the co-operation between Mitsubishi's trading, oil
exploration and oil refining arms in making, off the coast of Vietnam last
June, the largest oil discovery by a Japanese company for 35 years.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Mitsubishi Corp.
    Mitsubishi Heavy Industries.
    Mitsubishi Estate.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>JPZ  Japan, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6719 Holding Companies, NEC.
    P6552 Subdividers and Developers, Ex Cemeteries.
    P3731 Ship Building and Repairing.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 15
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6318</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK3EKACZFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941130
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  30 NOV 94 / Observer: Nothing sacred
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Mad cows, friendless in Britain, might try Indonesia, where supermarket
shelves carry a corned beef called GaGa.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>IDZ  Indonesia, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P2013 Sausages and Other Prepared Meats.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>TECH  Products &amp; Product use.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 15
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6348</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK3EKAB5FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941130
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  30 NOV 94 / People: Electronic switches
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Mark Bell, formerly vice-president Spectrum Enterprises for US West, has
been appointed deputy md of MERCURY ONE-2-ONE.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Mercury One-2-One.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P4812 Radiotelephone Communications.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 12
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6357</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK3EKABWFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941130
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  30 NOV 94 / Imposters 'prey on rate fears'
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Bogus rating consultants are defrauding small businesses ahead of next
year's business rate revaluation, professional rating bodies said yesterday.
Mr Colin Farrington, director of the Institute of Revenues, Rating and
Valuation, said unqualified people were setting themselves up as
'consultants', and in some cases 'absconding with clients' money'.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P8748 Business Consulting, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 8
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6378</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK3EKABBFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941130
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  30 NOV 94 / Japan joint venture in UK
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By EMIKO TERAZONO
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   TOKYO
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Toray Industries, the Japanese textile maker, plans to set up a textile
printing joint venture with Komatsu Seiren, a Japanese printing company of
synthetic fabrics. The venture, with total capital of Y4.5bn (Pounds 28.9m),
will invest Y1.1bn in a polyester filament printing plant, to start
operations in Nottingham by 1996. The plant will employ 50 local workers and
Japanese staff, Toray said.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Toray Industries.
    Komatsu Seiren.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>JPZ  Japan, Asia.
    GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P2282 Throwing and Winding Mills.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Strategic links &amp; Joint venture.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 6
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-268</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL3DMABDFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941230
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  30 DEC 94 / Thai, Malaysian ratings boost
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By CONNER MIDDELMANN
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   LONDON
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Standard &amp; Poors, the rating agency, has raised its credit ratings for
Thailand and Malaysia's long-term foreign-currency debt. Malaysia's rating
was raised to single-A-plus from single-A while Thailand's rating was raised
to single-A from single-A-minus, with a stable long-term outlook for both.
Malaysia's upgrading reflects the country's steady progress in diversifying
its export-based economy, prudent macroeconomic management and a political
system that balances the demands of its multi-ethnic society, the agency
said. Thailand's upgrading reflects the maintenance of the country's
external payments position and the consolidation of civilian-led democratic
rule since 1992.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>THZ  Thailand, Asia.
    MYZ  Malaysia, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9311 Finance, Taxation, and Monetary Policy.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 5
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-288</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL3DMAATFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941230
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  30 DEC 94 / N Korea frees pilot after US 'regrets' border intrusion
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By JUREK MARTIN and JOHN BURTON
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   WASHINGTON
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
North Korea early today released a US airman whose helicopter went down over
the communist state nearly two weeks ago.
His release appeared to defuse the fresh diplomatic row that flared up
between Pyongyang and Washington only two months after they had finalised an
accord on the North's nuclear programme.
The pilot, Chief Warrant Officer Bobby Hall, crossed the border at Panmunjom
into South Korea. His release came after the US sent a senior envoy, Mr
Thomas Hubbard, to Pyongyang on Wednesday for negotiations.
A Washington official said the US had expressed 'sincere regret' for the
helicopter's violation of North Korean air space. It agreed to hold contacts
with the North in an 'appropriate forum' to prevent similar incidents in the
future.
The US believes the existing Military Armistice Commission, set up after the
Korean War, should be the forum for such contacts. But North Korea could
well press for separate bilateral talks.
The North Koreans have insisted that the two US pilots - one of whom was
killed when their helicopter came down - were on a spying mission and they
published a 'confession' from Mr Hall.
In his ambiguous confession, Mr Hall admitted that his reconnaissance
helicopter made an 'intrusion deep' into North Korean airspace, adding 'this
criminal action is inexcusable and unpardonable'.
But any further delay in his release might have increased chances of the new
Republican-controlled US Congress trying to block implementation of the US
nuclear accord with North Korea. Under this accord, Pyongyang agreed to
dismantle its nuclear programme in return for US diplomatic ties and
international economic aid.
The pilot's apology may have provided a face-saving means for his release
while allowing North Korea to exploit the incident for propaganda purposes
and justify its downing of the helicopter.
The statement, if it was dictated by North Korean officials as many believe,
did not offer much support for Pyongyang's allegation that the helicopter
was on a spying mission and that its intrusion was deliberate.
Mr Hall's statement said his helicopter 'deviated' from its planned flight
route within South Korea, but gave no explanation why it strayed across the
demilitarised zone into the North. This could imply support for the US claim
that the helicopter lost its way due to a navigational error.
But some South Korean government analysts believe Mr Hall's statement that
it was on an 'observation reconnaissance' mission could be interpreted as
espionage if North Korea decides to press the affair.
North Korea may possibly exploit the incident to support its demand that the
US sign a formal treaty ending the 1950-53 Korean war and begin withdrawing
its 37,000 troops from South Korea.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>USZ  United States of America.
    KPZ  North Korea, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9721 International Affairs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 3
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-291</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL3DMAAQFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941230
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  30 DEC 94 / Pilot's confession may complicate his release from North
Korea
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By JOHN BURTON
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   HONG KONG
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
An ambiguous 'confession' signed by a US army helicopter pilot captured by
North Korea almost two weeks ago could further complicate efforts to secure
his release.
Analysts were divided over whether the statement by Chief Warrant Officer
Bobby Hall would speed his release or provide Pyongyang with new grounds to
detain him in return for possible concessions from the US.
If his return is delayed further, it is likely to increase prospects that
the new Republican-controlled US Congress will try to block implementation
of the recent US nuclear accord with North Korea. Under the accord,
Pyongyang agreed to dismantle its nuclear programme in return for US
diplomatic ties and international economic aid.
Mr Hall admitted that his OH-58 reconnaissance helicopter made an 'intrusion
deep' into North Korean airspace, adding 'this criminal action is
inexcusable and unpardonable'.
'I only hope, and it is my desire, that the (North) Korean People's Army
will leniently forgive me for my illegal intrusion so that I may return to
my home and be with my family again,' he concluded.
The apology may provide a face-saving means for his release, while allowing
North Korea to exploit the incident for propaganda purposes and justify its
downing of the helicopter.
The statement, if it was dictated by North Korean officials as many believe,
does not offer much support for Pyongyang's allegation that the helicopter
was on a spying mission and that its intrusion was deliberate. Mr Hall's
statement said that his helicopter 'deviated' from its planned flight route
within South Korea, but gave no explanation for why the helicopter strayed
across the demilitarised zone. This could imply support for the US claim
that the helicopter lost its way after a navigational error.
But some South Korean government analysts believe that Mr Hall's statement
that the helicopter was on an 'observation reconnaissance' mission could be
interpreted as espionage if North Korea decided to press the affair.
Whether North Korea will try to use the issue to gain concessions from the
US is still unclear as it negotiates with a senior US diplomat who has
travelled to Pyongyang to gain the pilot's release.
North Korea may possibly exploit the incident to support its demand that the
US sign a formal treaty ending the 1950-53 Korean war and begin withdrawing
its 37,000 troops from South Korea.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>HKZ  Hong Kong, Asia.
    KPZ  North Korea, Asia.
    USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9721 International Affairs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 3
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-301</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL3DMAAGFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941230
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  30 DEC 94 / World News in Brief: Holidaymakers killed
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Five British tourists on a skiing holiday were killed in a road accident
near Nice, southern France.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>FRZ  France, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9229 Public Order and Safety, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-302</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL3DMAAFFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941230
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  30 DEC 94 / World News in Brief: Flood threat recedes
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Flood alerts were scaled down as river levels fell and better weather
started to move across Britain. Weather forecast, Page 14
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9511 Air, Water, and Solid Waste Management.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-303</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL3DMAAEFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941230
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  30 DEC 94 / World News in Brief: Copper price reaches six-year high
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Copper prices, already boosted by strong industrial demand, traded at their
highest level for nearly six years in London as speculative buyers took
advantage of thin end-of-year business to push the market above Dollars
3,000 a tonne. Prices touched Dollars 3,022, 2 per cent up from
pre-Christmas levels and the highest since April 1989, before closing at
Dollars 3,012, up Dollars 18. Demand is forecast to grow by more than 3 per
cent next year but copper stocks should fall because no new mine or refinery
output will be on stream until the second half of 1995. Commodities, Page 21
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P1021 Copper Ores.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COSTS  Commodity prices.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-304</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL3DMAADFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941230
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  30 DEC 94 / World News in Brief: 54 die in Turkish air crash
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Fifty-four people died and 22 were injured when a Turkish Airlines Boeing
737 crashed into a mountain during a snowstorm at Van in eastern Turkey.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>TRZ  Turkey, Middle East.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9229 Public Order and Safety, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-324</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL2CVADSFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941229
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 DEC 94 / Commodities and Agriculture: Russia 'to scrap oil export
quotas from January 1'
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By REUTERS
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   MOSCOW
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
The Russian government will scrap oil export quotas soon and oblige
producers to supply up to 65 per cent of their crude oil output to domestic
refineries in the first quarter of next year, Interfax news agency said,
reports Reuters from Moscow.
It quoted Mr Andrei Dogayev, deputy foreign economic relations minister, as
saying that a resolution, due to take effect on January 1, had already been
'definitively agreed'.
Mr Dogayev said that crude oil and refined oil product exports would
continue to be regulated by tariffs and other methods.
The system of 'special exporters', under which all oil exports must go
through a limited number of approved companies, would be maintained, he
said, adding that 14 companies currently had the right to export crude oil.
The World Bank and the International Monetary Fund have opposed the special
exporter system and compulsory supplies to domestic consumers, linking
further credits to Russia to liberalisation of the oil export system.
Mr Dogayev doubted that the lifting of oil export quotas would lead to a
significant increase in exports at the expense of the domestic market. He
said that exports would be limited by demand factors and the capacity of oil
export pipelines.
Russian oil pipelines are reported to have been pumping at close to capacity
this year to the main export ports of Novorossiisk and Ventspils.
There is some unused capacity on the Druzhba pipeline route to eastern
Europe, but slumping demand there has curtailed deliveries in this
direction.
Last year's crude exports outside the former Soviet Union were about 80m
tonnes and officials say this year's figure will be more than 85m tonnes.
Mr Boris Yeltsin, Russian president, issued a decree in May abolishing
export quotas and licences from July. But he postponed putting the move into
effect until January amid widespread concern that producers would rush to
export and leave domestic enterprises without fuel. Domestic crude oil
prices are less than a third of world market levels.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>RUZ  Russia, East Europe.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P1311 Crude Petroleum and Natural Gas.
    P4612 Crude Petroleum Pipelines.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>RES  Natural resources.
    MKTS  Foreign trade.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 17
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-355</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL2CVACXFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941229
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 DEC 94 / UK Company News: Doeflex
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
DOEFLEX has bought Berryplas, a Droitwich, Worcestershire-based plastic
profile extruder, for Pounds 341,000, of which Pounds 69,500 is deferred
until one year after completion.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Doeflex.
    Berryplas.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3089 Plastics Products, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Mergers &amp; acquisitions.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 12
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-369</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL2CVACJFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941229
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 DEC 94 / UK Company News: Fisons downgraded by IBCA
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
IBCA, the European rating agency, has downgraded the long term rating of
Fisons, the drugs and scientific equipment company, from BBB+ to BBB. The
short term rating remains unchanged at A2.
IBCA said that Fisons' profits warnings with the interim results announced
in September, came after four years of deteriorating income coverage ratios.
'With only limited cash generated by operations, it is difficult to see
where long term support for the large capital and R&amp;D expenditure will come
from, although in the short term further disposals could be made,' IBCA
said.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Fisons.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P2834 Pharmaceutical Preparations.
    P3821 Laboratory Apparatus and Furniture.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 12
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-403</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL2CVABLFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941229
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 DEC 94 / Cost of house insurance develops a bout of subsidence: What
is good news for consumers is less so for shareholders
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By RALPH ATKINS
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Sales fever is spreading to house insurance.
Halifax, the UK's largest building society, last week announced cuts
averaging 20 per cent for building cover. Since then evidence has grown of
an escalating price war.
AA Insurance, which sells policies on behalf of 40 insurers, yesterday said
the average cost of house contents policies had fallen by more than 1 per
cent since July. It would have been greater if the 2.5 per cent Insurance
Premium Tax had not been imposed in October.
The AA's latest insurance price survey, due for release early next year,
shows rates for building insurance policies dropping by about 2.5 per cent
since July, excluding IPT.
Churchill Insurance, one of the new breed of 'direct insurers' selling via
the telephone and cutting out brokers' commissions, said its buildings
policies were 7 per cent cheaper than a year ago. Contents premiums have
fallen 2 per cent.
Cornhill Insurance, which offers building and contents insurance, yesterday
announced that it was following Halifax's lead in offering no-claims
discounts on some household policies as well as discounts for older
policyholders.
Such signs are good news for consumers who, in recent years, have become
accustomed to crime and bad weather leading to rapidly rising insurance
premiums. They are less welcome for shareholders, who have seen profit
forecasts cut for large insurance companies - many of which have only
recently returned to making healthy profits.
Several factors are increasing competition. Most obviously, fast-growing
'direct' sellers such as Churchill and Royal Bank of Scotland's Direct Line
are anxious to build market share in the home insurance sector. But
consumers are also becoming more price sensitive.
Traditionally, most structure and contents policies have been sold by
building societies at the same time as mortgages. More than half of people
taking out combined policies for the first time continue to use this route,
according to a survey earlier this year by NOP, the polling organisation.
But the number of policyholders switching from one company to another -
currently about 10 per cent a year - is increasing, NOP suggested.
Worryingly for banks and building societies, which in recent years have
enjoyed healthy profits from selling insurance products, about 21 per cent
of 'switchers' choose direct insurers.
Such trends explain Halifax's high-profile price cuts last week. But
building societies have another reason for examining the cost of insurance
products they sell. From next year Treasury rules are expected to allow
societies to underwrite, as well as distribute, insurance policies.
That will put pressure on the current system by which societies sell polices
provided by composite insurers (most of Halifax home insurance products, for
instance, are supplied by Sun Alliance). There will be a big incentive for
societies to cut costs and take a greater share of profits by becoming
insurers in their own right.
Certainly the scope for cutting household insurance premiums further is
considerable. Over the past year insurance companies have benefited not only
from higher premiums set in previous years, but also from a dramatic fall in
subsidence claims, helped by wetter weather. Theft has fallen too, while
natural disasters have been infrequent.
Computers allow insurers to assess risks more accurately, enabling them to
set premiums almost on a household by household basis. For instance, Royal
Insurance says it uses all the characters of postcodes to judge likely
claims.
Typically, insurance companies are this year reporting underwriting profits
of about 20 per cent on household insurance premiums - far higher than for
most other insurance products. Profit margins are still higher when income
earned by insurance companies from investing premiums is added. Building
societies and brokers take another slice of the price paid by policyholders.
The size of that cushion illustrates the room for insurers cutting prices
next year - and still making a decent return. 'You can halve the profit
margin and it's still very exciting,' said Mr John Chester, insurance expert
at SG Warburg.
But as they cut premiums, insurers will have at least half an eye on the
longer term. Household insurance policies have to make substantial returns
most years because once in a while there is a large natural disaster
resulting in big losses. The UK has escaped lightly in recent years so there
are insurance bargains to be had. But good times cannot last for ever.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6331 Fire, Marine, and Casualty Insurance.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COSTS  Product costs &amp; Product prices.
    CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 4
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-419</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL2CVAA5FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941229
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 DEC 94 / US envoy presses North Korea to release pilot
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By JOHN BURTON
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   HONG KONG
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
A senior US diplomat arrived in Pyongyang yesterday to seek the release of a
US army pilot whose detention by North Korea threatens its recent nuclear
agreement with Washington.
The visit by Mr Thomas Hubbard, a deputy assistant secretary of state,
follows that of a US congressman who last week helped to arrange the return
of the body of the pilot's colleague, killed in the crash of their
helicopter in North Korea.
North Korea has said that it has delayed the repatriation of the captured
pilot, Chief Warrant Officer Bobby Hall, because he has not co-operated in
its investigation of the straying of the OH-58 reconnaissance helicopter
into its airspace.
Pyongyang claims the helicopter was on a spying mission and the North has
demanded an acknowledgement of guilt and an apology from the US. Last night
North Korea said the pilot had confessed to intruding deep into its
territory on a reconnaissance mission and had asked for forgiveness. The
official news agency quoted Hall as saying: 'I admit that this criminal
action is inexcusable and unpardonable. However, at home my parents, wife
and kids are anxiously waiting for my return.'
Washington said the helicopter flew into North Korea because of a
navigational error.
Analysts believe other reasons may account for North Korea's reluctance to
release the pilot. One possibility is that North Korea is trying to exploit
the incident to gain new concessions from the US. Pyongyang has been
pressing Washington to sign a peace treaty that would formally end the
Korean war of 1950-53, in the hope that this would eventually lead to the
withdrawal of the 37,000 US troops in South Korea.
North Korea could argue that the helicopter incident underscores the need
for such a peace treaty.
It may also try to use the incident as a means to force the US to accelerate
the establishment of diplomatic ties with Pyongyang, as promised under the
bilateral nuclear accord concluded in October.
The US also agreed to guarantee international aid, including the supply of
safer light-water reactors, if North Korea dismantled its current nuclear
programme, which is suspected of producing weapons-grade plutonium.
However, such a diplomatic strategy carries risks for North Korea since US
congressional critics of the nuclear agreement may use the continued
detention of the pilot as a reason to block the deal.
US critics of the accord believe that it offers too many concessions to
North Korea. Senator Bob Dole, who is soon to become US Senate majority
leader, was quoted yesterday as calling the agreement 'a lousy deal' and
adding, 'you can't trust the North Koreans'.
Mr Lee Hamilton, outgoing chairman of the US House of Representatives
foreign relations committee, said: 'I don't think we'd proceed with our side
of the nuclear accord if they don't release the airman.'
Even so, the delay may also reflect deep divisions between North Korea
leaders over the nuclear agreement. Some South Korean officials believe that
the Northern military is at odds with its government over whether to proceed
with the agreement.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>KPZ  North Korea, Asia.
    USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9721 International Affairs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 3
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-430</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL2CVAAUFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941229
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 DEC 94 / German import prices rise
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By ANDREW FISHER
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   FRANKFURT
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
West German import prices moved up sharply between October and November,
bearing out the Bundesbank's determination to combat future inflation as
expressed in its money supply target for 1995. The November import price
level was 0.8 per cent above that for the previous month and 2.2 per cent
above November 1993, the federal statistics office said. The yearly rate was
higher than the 1.9 per cent in both September and October. Producer prices
have also been rising more rapidly. Both indicators suggest a later upturn
in inflation.
The central bank stressed its commitment to reaching its medium-term
inflation goal of 2 per cent when setting its M3 target last week. Athough
the 1995 target range is unchanged at 4-6 per cent, achieving it will mean a
slower average rate of money supply growth than in 1994. The strong upturn
in the economy this year has revived uneasiness about future inflation,
although the rate of consumer price growth has been slowing. Provisional
figures from four west German states showed a 2.7 per cent annual inflation
rate in December (as in November) and the Bundesbank expects this to ease to
under 2.5 per cent early next year. The average for 1994 was 3 per cent, the
statistics office said.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>DEZ  Germany, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9311 Finance, Taxation, and Monetary Policy.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>STATS  Statistics.
    ECON  Inflation.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 2
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-441</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL2CVAAJFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941229
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 DEC 94 / World News in Brief: Fanny Cradock dies
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Fanny Cradock, a pioneer of cookery programmes with BBC television, died in
an East Sussex nursing home, aged 85. She and husband Johnny, who died in
1987, first appeared on television in 1955.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P99   Nonclassifiable Establishments.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  People.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-526</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL1B9ABHFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941228
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  28 DEC 94 / MP protests over Mercury offer
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
The Labour MP, Mr Andrew MacKinlay, said yesterday he would protest to Mr
Michael Heseltine, trade and industry secretary, about the fact that
thousands of people who had been 'enticed' into purchasing a Mercury
One-2-One mobile telephone on the promise of unlimited free calls on
Christmas day could not get through.
Mercury One-2-One said at least 20 people had spent more than 12 hours on
the phone on Christmas day. Another 20 had made more than 2,000 calls
between them.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Mercury Communications.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9651 Regulation of Miscellaneous Commercial Sectors.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Company News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 6
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-527</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL1B9ABGFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941228
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  28 DEC 94 / Cornhill cuts its home premiums
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Cornhill Insurance is the latest insurance company to reduce household
insurance premiums. The company is introducing no-claims discounts of up to
20 per cent on buildings and contents insurance from January 1 and special
discounts for older customers.
Last week Halifax Building Society announced it was cutting buildings
insurance premiums by an average of 20 per cent from the new year.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Cornhill Insurance.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6331 Fire, Marine, and Casualty Insurance.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COSTS  Product costs &amp; Product prices.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 6
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-532</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL1B9ABBFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941228
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  28 DEC 94 / Thomson joins holiday price war
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Thomson, Britain's biggest tour company, yesterday offered summer breaks for
as little as Pounds 99 as the holiday price war built up.
Going Places, the second biggest travel retailer, has already announced
discounts on overseas summer holidays of up to 20 per cent.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Thomson Holidays.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P4725 Tour Operators.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>MGMT  Management &amp; Marketing.
    COSTS  Product costs &amp; Product prices.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 6
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-552</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL1B9AARFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941228
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  28 DEC 94 / Talks today on release of US pilot
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By JUREK MARTIN, US Editor
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   WASHINGTON
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
A senior US state department official arrived last night in South Korea, en
route for talks in North Korea today when he will seek the release of Chief
Warrant Officer Bobby Hall, the US army helicopter pilot downed over the
North on December 17.
Mr Thomas Hubbard, a deputy assistant secretary of state, was part of the US
team that reached the agreement on nuclear non-proliferation with North
Korea in October. He was sent on his new mission after North Korean
diplomats at the UN had suggested that this would 'facilitate a resolution'
of the problem.
But broadcasts and statements from Pyongyang over the last 48 hours have
alleged that the helicopter was on a spying mission and have demanded that
the US admit as much. US officials have maintained that it strayed into
North Korea while on routine training because of a navigational error. Even
so, the US has apologised for the violation of the North's air space.
Congressman Bill Richardson, the New Mexico Democrat who brought home the
body of the other US pilot killed in the incident, said the new mission
could strengthen the hand of the North Korean foreign ministry, adding that
it was more eager for a resolution than was the North's military command.
Mr Lee Hamilton, outgoing chairman of the House of Representatives foreign
affairs committee, warned yesterday that Congress might delay a scheduled US
oil shipment to Pyongyang so as to force the release of the pilot.
The US is to provide 50,000 tons of heavy fuel oil, valued at about Dollars
4.7m (Pounds 3m), to North Korea by January 21 as part of the October
accord.
However, the US is anxious not to jeopardise the hard-won agreement which
appeared to remove the immediate threat of the North acquiring an offensive
nuclear capability.
There has been speculation here about a continuing internal power struggle
in Pyongyang after the death last summer of Kim Il-sung ended 45 years of
his authoritarian rule. Kim Jong-il, his son and successor, has been seen
only intermittently in recent weeks.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>KRZ  South Korea, Asia.
    KPZ  North Korea, Asia.
    USZ  United States of America.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9721 International Affairs.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 3
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-574</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EL1B9ADOFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941224
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  24 DEC 94 / Arts: FT Christmas Arts quiz
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
1. To general approval, 1994 saw the back of a baroness on the move and
three bottoms remaining stationary. Who was the baroness and whose were the
bottoms?
2. Who redealt the cards to play the king on television?
3. What did WH Smith find suitable in March?
4. What did Bruce Land Rambert with in May?
5. What became live in March, having been moribund before?
6. Which debutant promenaded for the first time at the age of 85?
7. And which Deb's efforts were booed at Glyndebourne?
8. If all's the world a stage, what part of it did the Globe become?
9. Which artist's ovine conservation was not quite what organic farmers had
in mind?
10. Which turkey in Shaftesbury Avenue failed to live up to its name?
11. But whose pound of flesh turned out to be prime turkey?
12. Which dead poet became a best seller after someone else's funeral?
13. Which dead pianist became a star times 32?
14. Which ark developed a list but carried off the prizes?
15. Who took literary pursuits as far as doorstepping?
16. Which famous screamer was outed in Norway (but went in again)?
17. Which Partridge changed its perch?
18. Writing to the press caught on. What prompted (a) the art establishment
to write to the London Evening Standard? and (b) 87 writers to contact The
Guardian?
19. Who left one Nirvana in the hope of finding another?
20. Who left the boulevard under a cloud without enjoying the sunset?
21. Which knight's knight wouldn't be shouted down in Bow Street?
22. Which septuagenarian upstaged someone else's birthday party on the South
Bank?
23. Which little film camera boldly went where (one hopes) no camera had
been before?
24. How did Alan's meeting with Alain damage their health?
Answers on page VII
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P99   Nonclassifiable Establishments.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page VI
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-593</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-ELXAIAEHFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941224
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  24 DEC 94 / Weekend Money: Money watch
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
 -----------------------------------------------------------------------
                                                  6 mths       Year
                                 Latest value        ago        ago
 -----------------------------------------------------------------------
Retail Prices Index*/***                 +2.6       +2.5       +1.4
Halifax House Price Indx**/***           -1.0        0.0       +1.5
Halifax mortgage rate (%)                8.10       7.64       7.99
Base lending rate (%)                   6 1/4      5 1/4      5 1/2
3-mth interbank mid rate (%)          6 11/32      5 1/8     5 5/16
10-year gilt yield                       8.49       8.63       6.17
Long gilt/equity yld ratio (%)           2.15       2.12       1.83
Dollars/Pounds exchange rate           1.5468     1.5421     1.5020
Dm/Pounds exchange rate                2.4412     2.4630     2.5450
Gold price (Dollars per oz)            381.30     391.70     386.75
 -----------------------------------------------------------------------
  * RPI for Nov.
 ** All Houses index shown for Nov.
*** Annual % change.
 -----------------------------------------------------------------------
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9311 Finance, Taxation, and Monetary Policy.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>STATS  Statistics.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page XII
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6478</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK2CXAGRFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941129
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 NOV 94 / International Company News: Pearl Tyre offering takes ASX
closer to 'Asian board'
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By NIKKI TAIT
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   SYDNEY
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Efforts by the Australian Stock Exchange (ASX) to secure enough foreign
listings to form a special 'Asian board' within its local stock market took
another step forward yesterday when Pearl River Tyre, a Chinese tyre
business, announced plans for a ADollars 45.2m (USDollars 33.4m) share
offering.
Pearl River is a Bermuda-based company formed to hold a 70 per cent interest
in Guangzhou Pearl River Tyre. GPRT, in turn, is based in Guangdong province
and makes tyres for buses and other commercial vehicles. The remaining 30
per cent of GPRT is owned by Guangzhou city, which was formerly the sole
ultimate owner of the tyre business.
Pearl River is planning to sell 45.2m shares at ADollars 1 each. This stock
will represent 86 per cent of the company's issued capital, and the balance
will be held by the government of Guangzhou and professional advisers
involved in the transaction. A group of Malaysian businessmen has already
agreed to subscribe for some 18.4m shares, and a similar amount has been
placed with international institutional investors. This leaves about 10m
shares available for the general public.
The money raised will be used to double the company's production capacity by
1997, from about 1m tyres a year at present.
Sales in 1994 are expected to be about ADollars 60m.
The listing, which is expected to take place early in 1995, will mean that
about half a dozen 'China concept' stocks trade on the ASX, with Pearl River
being the largest.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Pearl River Tyre.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>AUZ  Australia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6231 Security and Commodity Exchanges.
    P3011 Tires and Inner Tubes.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>FIN  Share issues.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 31
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6562</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK2CXAEEFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941129
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 NOV 94 / Observer: Blacked
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
British Coal may be out of business by Christmas Eve but it still seems to
have a few scores to settle. Gerard McCloskey, the editor of several
Financial Times newsletters on coal, currently engaged in some acrimonious
exchanges with RJB Mining, also seems to have upset Neil Clarke, British
Coal's outgoing chairman. McCloskey has been dropped from the guest list for
British Coal's last Christmas lunch for journalists. Come on lads, isn't it
time to bury the hatchet?
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>British Coal Corp.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P8999 Services, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  People.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 21
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6594</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK2CXADIFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941129
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 NOV 94 / People: Non-executive directors
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Robin Burleigh, senior partner of Clifford Chance, at FIRST NATIONAL FINANCE
CORPORATION.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>First National Finance Corp.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6411 Insurance Agents, Brokers, and Service.
    P6159 Miscellaneous Business Credit Institutions.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  Appointments.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 18
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6596</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK2CXADGFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941129
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 NOV 94 / People: Non-executive directors
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
David Hewitt has retired from COLORVISION.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>Colorvision.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P5064 Electrical Appliances, Television and Radios.
    P5722 Household Appliance Stores.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  People.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 18
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6597</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK2CXADFFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941129
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 NOV 94 / People: Non-executive directors
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Philip Kaye has retired from CITY CENTRE RESTAURANTS.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>City Centre Restaurants.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P5812 Eating Places.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>PEOP  People.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 18
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6607</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK2CXAC5FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941129
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 NOV 94 / Technology: Closing in on a serial killer - Cancer kills
five people every minute of the day. In the first of a six-part series,
Clive Cookson reports on the war against cancer and the encouraging trends
behind the statistics
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By CLIVE COOKSON
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Cancer continues to sink its claws deeper into mankind. After two decades of
'war on cancer', fuelled by billions of research dollars, the death toll
rises inexorably.
The disease - named after the Latin word for crab because of the crab-like
pattern made by blood vessels on a growing tumour - will kill an estimated
2.5m people in the industrialised world this year. That amounts to almost a
quarter of all deaths.
The gloomy mortality statistics contrast with excitement among cancer
researchers, who have made more progress towards understanding the
fundamental processes responsible for the disease over the past 15 years
than in all previous history. The important question for present and future
cancer patients is how quickly the new knowledge can be converted into
better diagnosis and treatment.
At present there is a gap between doctors' continuing inability to provide
much more than palliative care for millions of cancer patients and the
cascade of optimistic stories in the popular media about 'breakthroughs' in
research, such as discovering cancer genes and inventing experimental drugs.
There is an inevitable delay - typically a decade or so - while an advance
in medical science is developed for commercial application. So no one should
expect the latest discoveries to have made any clinical impact yet. But many
people will remember 'breakthroughs' from the 1970s and early 1980s, such as
interferon and 'magic bullet' antibodies, which would have transformed
cancer treatment by now - if they had lived up to first expectations.
Very few patients are treated with novel approaches derived from
biotechnology. The vast majority still undergo the well-established
procedures of chemotherapy (poisoning cancer cells with a drug cocktail) and
radiotherapy (destroying them with radiation). Surgery is also used to cut
out solid tumours.
'We hear the word 'breakthrough' thrown around too much,' says Nicholas
Wright, clinical director of the Imperial Cancer Research Fund in London,
'and we certainly get the impression that the public are a bit jaundiced by
scientists talking about breakthroughs.'
Why are more people contracting and dying from cancer? The first reason is
an epidemic of cancers caused by smoking, particularly lung cancer. 'At
least 30 per cent of all cancer deaths are tobacco-related,' says Archie
Turnbull, executive secretary of the Geneva-based UICC, an umbrella body for
the world's cancer charities.
A second, more fundamental, reason is that cancer is mainly a disease of old
age. As medicine becomes more successful at preventing early deaths from
other illnesses such as heart attacks and strokes, more people are living
beyond the age of 70, above which the risk of cancer rises rapidly.
Despite the overall rise in cancer mortality, there have been substantial
improvements in some areas. The most encouraging feature of the statistics
since the 1970s is the progress in curing cancers in children and young
adults - particularly leukaemia, Hodgkin's disease and testicular cancer -
through new drug combinations. The number of children under the age of 15
dying from cancer has fallen by half.
There are two principal reasons why young people are responding more readily
to treatment. One is that youthful cancer cells in the blood or lymph
systems are physically easier to reach and destroy with drugs and/or
radiation than the solid tumours of the middle-aged and elderly. Another
reason is that the difference between proliferating cancer cells and normal
cells is greater in childhood cancers than in slower-growing adult tumours.
Therefore chemotherapy and radiotherapy, which work by damaging DNA during
cell division, can destroy more cancer cells without causing unacceptable
side-effects.
Prospects for curing the big killers - tumours of the lungs, bowels,
stomach, breast, prostate and pancreas - depend above all on developing
treatments that discriminate more effectively between cancer and normal
cells than the drugs used in chemotherapy today.
The discovery of genetic changes leading to cancer should make this
possible, says Gordon McVie, scientific director of the Cancer Research
Campaign. 'These provide for the first time an absolute chemical difference
between the cells. Until now we have had to rely on qualitative differences
 -the cancer cells making rather more of some proteins and less of others.'
Scientists have identified more than 100 genes that can trigger the cellular
processes leading to cancer, if they mutate. (Causes of mutation include
carcinogenic chemicals, radiation, family inheritance, and random changes
during cell division.)
One dangerous type of genetic change stimulates cell growth. Another shuts
down the protective 'tumour suppressor' genes which normally prevent
excessive proliferation. The former has been compared with a car that has
its accelerator jammed on, the latter with a failure in the brakes.
New approaches to the prevention, diagnosis and treatment of cancer are
being built on such differences between the genes of diseased and normal
cells - and the corresponding differences in the proteins they produce. One
possibility is to block the damaging effects of abnormal 'growth factors'
which sustain the proliferation of tumour cells, without harming healthy
cell growth.
But cancer genes are not the only reason why researchers are excited.
Another is their new understanding of the way the body's immune system
recognises and attacks cancer cells. This has led to experimental 'cancer
vaccines' to boost the immune response.
These novel 'biotech' approaches to cancer diagnosis and treatment will be
examined over the next six months on the Financial Times technology page. So
will advances in more conventional chemotherapy and radiotherapy.
The aim is to convey the real optimism that now prevails in the laboratories
 -a hope and expectation that cancer will eventually be restricted to a
disease of the very old - without raising excessive expectations about the
speed and ease with which this will happen.
After 50 years in cancer research, Sir Richard Doll of the ICRF Cancer
Studies Unit in Oxford sums up the mood: 'We are winning the war against
cancer, albeit slowly.'
 ----------------------------------------------------------------------
CAUSES OF DEATH
In developed countries (1990)
 ----------------------------------------------------------------------
Cardiovascular                    5.36m
Other diseases                    2.76m
Cancer                            2.45m
Accidents, murder and suicide     0.87m
 ----------------------------------------------------------------------
 ----------------------------------------------------------------------
DEATHS BY CANCER
In developed countries ('000s)
 ----------------------------------------------------------------------
Mouth and pharynx                           52
Oesophagus                                  62
Stomach                                    244
Large intestine                            273
Liver                                       55
Pancreas                                   118
Larynx                                      33
Lung                                       530
Melanoma                                    23
Breast                                     177
Cervix                                      33
Other uterus                                38
Ovary                                       60
Prostate                                   110
Bladder                                     63
Other &amp; ill-defined                        406
Hodgkin's disease                            8
Other lymphoma &amp; myeloma                    89
Leukaemia                                   76
ALL CANCER                               2,450
 ----------------------------------------------------------------------
Source: WHO, ICRF
 ----------------------------------------------------------------------
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>XAZ  World.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9431 Administration of Public Health Programs.
    P8731 Commercial Physical Research.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 17
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6608</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK2CXAC4FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941129
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 NOV 94 / Technology: Disease tops list of industry priorities
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By CLIVE COOKSON
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
The pharmaceutical industry is devoting huge resources to cancer research
and development, in relation to sales of existing drugs.
Although reliable figures are not available, industry sources estimate that
companies worldwide spend Dollars 3bn (Pounds 2bn) a year on cancer R&amp;D. US
companies are responsible for about half the total.
The cancer therapeutics market is worth about Dollars 6.5bn this year,
according to Frost &amp; Sullivan, the international market research company: 38
per cent in the US, 26 per cent in Europe and 36 per cent in the rest of the
world.
The leading suppliers are Zeneca of the UK (whose tamoxifen was the best
selling-cancer drug with Dollars 550m sales in 1993) and Bristol-Myers
Squibb of the US.
'Devoting almost 50 per cent of sales revenues to R&amp;D is a very high figure
indeed,' says David Barrett, Bristol-Myers Squibb's strategic projects
director. The industry's overall R&amp;D expenditure is 15 per cent of drug
sales.
The main reason why cancer spending is so high is that the disease is top of
the industry's priority list of 'unmet needs'. Although deaths from heart
disease are twice those from cancer, they are falling - and cardiologists
already have a much wider range of effective treatments than oncologists.
At the same time, scientific advances are giving many new leads both to
traditional drug companies and to the emerging biotechnology sector. The
world now has more than 1,000 experimental cancer drugs in the R&amp;D pipeline.
Analysts such as Decision Resources and Frost &amp; Sullivan predict continued
growth of more than 10 per cent a year in the cancer market into the next
century. It is expected to exceed Dollars 10bn by 1998.
The industry's cancer R&amp;D spending is matched by a further Dollars 3bn a
year from the world's governments and charities. By far the largest
contributor is the US National Cancer Institute, which receives Dollars 2bn
a year in federal funding.
The charitable sector is particularly important in the UK, where the
Imperial Cancer Research Fund and Cancer Research Campaign spend Pounds 100m
a year between them - 10 times as much as the state-funded Medical Research
Council.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>XAZ  World.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P8731 Commercial Physical Research.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>RES  R&amp;D spending.
    CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 17
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6654</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK2CXABUFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941129
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 NOV 94 / River Lagan bridge opened
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Belfast's new Pounds 29m rail link over the river Lagan opened yesterday.
The bridge spans 1 1/2 miles
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P4785 Inspection and Fixed Facilities.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>RES  Facilities.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 10
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6666</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK2CXABIFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941129
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 NOV 94 / Pyongyang 'has halted N-projects'
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By REUTER
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   VIENNA
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
North Korea has halted its nuclear programme and stopped building two
nuclear reactors in accordance with its landmark accord with the US, the
United Nations atomic safeguards agency said yesterday, Reuter reports from
Vienna. The International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) said inspectors who
arrived in North Korea last week had visited nuclear sites in the communist
state and confirmed all work had come to a halt.
'The IAEA team visited the nuclear facilities in Yongbyon and Taechon and
confirmed that these facilities were not in operation and that construction
work had stopped,' the IAEA said in a statement.
An IAEA team held a series of negotiations with North Korean officials aimed
at setting out an inspections framework to ensure Pyongyang was complying
with a nuclear agreement signed with Washington in Geneva last month. The
statement said some verification measures, which were understood to include
inspections, had already been carried out.
North Korea agreed to freeze its nuclear programme in return for western
help and cash to build light-water reactors which produce less of the
plutonium that can be used to make nuclear arms. The US and its allies
suspected that North Korea had syphoned off nuclear fuel from its one
working reactor in Yongbyon to try to develop an atomic bomb.
Pressure from the west and the IAEA earlier this year provoked one of the
most serious military standoffs on the Korean peninsula since the 1950-53
Korean war. The US-North Korean accord defused the crisis.
Under the deal, the US pledged to set up an international consortium with
Japan and South Korea to help pay for the estimated Dollars 4bn operation.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>KPZ  North Korea, Asia.
    ATZ  Austria, West Europe.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9721 International Affairs.
    P1629 Heavy Construction, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>RES  Facilities.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 8
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6676</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK2CXAA8FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941129
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  29 NOV 94 / World Trade News: GEC Alsthom Moteurs - Contracts
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By AFX
</BYLINE>
<DATELINE>
   TOKYO
</DATELINE>
<TEXT>
Japan's Electric Power Development said GEC Alsthom's unit, GEC Alsthom
Moteurs, has won a contract to supply two hydroelectric generators for the
8MW Saitsunaigawa river power plant.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>GEC Alsthom Moteurs.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>JPZ  Japan, Asia.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P3511 Turbines and Turbine Generator Sets.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>MKTS  Contracts.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 6
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6808</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK1C5ADDFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941128
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  28 NOV 94 / The Lex Column: German bunds
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
There was encouraging news for the German bond market last week. Growth in
October's M3 money supply worked out at an annualised rate of 6.9 per cent,
suggesting the Bundesbank will come close to meeting its target of 4 to 6
per cent M3 growth for the year. Year-on-year inflation was down to 2.6 per
cent in November - further progress towards the Bundesbank's 2 per cent
objective.
The favourable outlook is blighted somewhat by continuing uncertainty over
German fiscal policy, which cannot be cleared up until after the tight 1995
budget has been agreed later this month. The wage round for next year
presents another risk. But, given the backdrop of improving inflation and
money supply data, it is not absurd to suggest that the Bundesbank may cut
short-term rates one last time during the current economic cycle, perhaps
early next year. To some extent it does not matter whether short-term rates
are cut or not; sentiment towards bunds will improve even if rates are
merely left on hold throughout most of 1995. This seems more likely than the
monetary tightening still anticipated by the Euromarkets.
Improving fundamentals have helped bunds over recent months; they have
regained their traditional premium to comparable US issues. The
outperformance is more marked for US investors because of the weakness of
the dollar versus the D-Mark. This may encourage profit-taking at signs of a
pronounced rally, but if last week's tentative worldwide shift from equities
into bonds gathers momentum, bunds will clearly benefit.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>DEZ  Germany, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9311 Finance, Taxation, and Monetary Policy.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>CMMT  Comment &amp; Analysis.
    ECON  Inflation.
    ECON  Economic Indicators.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 20
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-6815</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK1C5AC6FT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941128
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  28 NOV 94 / Observer: Making up
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
All rather odd. Sir Donald Gosling, founder and major shareholder of
National Car Parks and the venture capitalists who had planned to buy his
company, are off to lunch at the Savoy on Friday to celebrate the collapse
of their Pounds 650m deal.
The occasion is the Saints and Sinners charity lunch. Is this a sly dig at
venture capitalist Prudential Venture Managers following its unwillingness
to put up the last Pounds 50m? Alternatively, maybe it is a belated
recognition by Gosling that NCP's second largest institutional shareholder
is probably worth keeping happy. Interesting to see who picks up the
champagne bill.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Companies:-
</XX>
<CO>National Car Parks.
    Prudential Venture Managers.
</CO>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6799 Investors, NEC.
    P7521 Automobile Parking.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>COMP  Company News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 19
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-7046</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK0AOACJFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941126
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  26 NOV 94 / Weekend Money (Financial Planning): Top annuity rates
</HEADLINE>
<BYLINE>
   By PETER QUINTON, Annuity Bureau
</BYLINE>
<TEXT>
Despite Generali increasing its annuity rates by 1.5%, the downward trend
has continued, writes Peter Quinton of the Annuity Bureau. Canada Life moved
its annuity rates down by 0.8% on November 21, and, on November 22, three
other life companies, London Life, Prudential and Abbey Life chose to reduce
their rates by 1.1%, 1% and 0.08%, respectively. The downward trend is in
part due to actuaries responding to a reduction in gilt yields.
An annuity provides a guaranteed income for life in return for a lump sum
investment. The bulk of the fund built up by many types of pension plan must
be used in this way. This week's table shows COMPULSORY PURCHASE ANNUITY
RATES which are used for small company schemes and additional voluntary
contribution plans (AVCs) and freestanding AVCs (FSAVCs) among others. This
week's rates include inflation proofing.
 -----------------------------------------------------------------------
Escalating at 5% pa               Escalating at 5% pa
Male age 55    Annuity (0%*)      Female age 50   Annuity (+2.1%*)
 -----------------------------------------------------------------------
RNPFN        Pounds 6,591.96      Sun Life         Pounds 5,411.64
Generali     Pounds 6,563.22      Prudential       Pounds 5,302.56
Sun Life     Pounds 6,532.68      Generali         Pounds 5,288.52
 -----------------------------------------------------------------------
Escalating at 5% pa               Escalating at 5% pa
Male age 60    Annuity (0%*)      Female age 60      Annuity (0%*)
 -----------------------------------------------------------------------
RNPFN        Pounds 7,663.44      RNPFN            Pounds 6,643.20
Generali     Pounds 7,490.68      Royal Life       Pounds 6,566.35
Royal Life   Pounds 7,449.21      Sun Life         Pounds 6,522.36
 -----------------------------------------------------------------------
Escalating at 3% pa               Escalating at 3% pa
Male age 70    Annuity (0%*)      Female age 70      Annuity (0%*)
 -----------------------------------------------------------------------
RNPFN       Pounds 12,691.92      RNPFN           Pounds 10,707.84
Royal Life  Pounds 12,048.07      Royal Life      Pounds 10,357.83
Sun Life    Pounds 11.883.00      Generali        Pounds 10,213.64
 -----------------------------------------------------------------------
JOINT LIFE - 100% SPOUSE'S BENEFIT
Escalating at 5% pa               Escalating at 5% pa
Male age 60                       Male age 65
Female age 57  Annuity (+2.4%*)   Female age 63   Annuity (+0.1%*)
 -----------------------------------------------------------------------
Sun Life        Pounds 5,702.88   Generali         Pounds 6,438.85
Generali        Pounds 5,697.44   RNPFN            Pounds 6,435.48
Royal Life      Pounds 5,609.77   Royal Life       Pounds 6,421.53
 -----------------------------------------------------------------------
*Month's movement
Payments are monthly in arrears, without a guarantee period. Rates are
at 22 November1994. Figures assume an annuity purchase price of Pounds
100,000 after paying and are shown gross. RNPFN annuities are available
only to nurses and allied workers.
Source: Annuity Bureau: 071-620 4090.
 -----------------------------------------------------------------------
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>GBZ  United Kingdom, EC.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P6311 Life Insurance.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>STATS  Statistics.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 9
</PAGE>
</DOC>

<DOC>
<DOCNO>FT944-7123</DOCNO>
<PROFILE>_AN-EK0AOAAEFT</PROFILE>
<DATE>941126
</DATE>
<HEADLINE>
FT  26 NOV 94 / World News in Brief: Rwandan refugees killed
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
Zairean troops killed at least eight Rwandan refugees, including four
children, when they opened fire at a camp north west of the Zairean border
town of Goma.
</TEXT>
<XX>
Countries:-
</XX>
<CN>RWZ  Rwanda, Africa.
    ZRZ  Zaire, Africa.
</CN>
<XX>
Industries:-
</XX>
<IN>P9229 Public Order and Safety, NEC.
</IN>
<XX>
Types:-
</XX>
<TP>NEWS  General News.
</TP>
<PUB>The Financial Times
</PUB>
<PAGE>
London Page 1
</PAGE>
</DOC>